本片根據真實事件改編
United 1523, did you hear your company... did you hear, uh...
1523隊 你聽見你的組織... 你聽到...
We did hear that yelling, too.
我們也聽見那喊叫了
We couldn't tell what it was either.
我們也不知道那是什麼
United 93...
93隊...
Has he turned to the east now?
他去東邊了嗎?
Please state your emergency.
請陳述您的緊急情況
2001年9月11日
The flight attendant is advising our reps
空服員讓我們報警求救
that the pilot and everyone's been stabbed.
飛行員和其他人都被刺傷了
And we can't breathe.
我們快窒息了
I don't know. I think we're getting hijacked.
我不知道 我想我們被劫持了
Hijacked aircraft headed towards New York.
被劫持的飛機正在向紐約飛去
- Is this real world or exercise?  - No, this is not an exercise.
- 這是真的還是演習?  - 不 這不是演習
Can anybody get up to the cockpit?
誰能去駕駛室看看?
What's going on, Betty?
出什麼事了 貝蒂?
Betty, talk to me.
貝蒂 說話啊
A plane just crashed into the World Trade Center.
一架飛機剛剛撞進世貿大樓了
I think we might have lost her.
我覺得她斷線了
Hey, Mom, I'm sure that you've heard
媽媽 你肯定聽說了
that a plane crashed into World Trade Center One.
一架飛機撞進了世貿一號大樓
We're fine. We're in World Trade Center Two.
我們沒事 我們在世貿二號樓
I'm on a plane that's been hijacked.
我在被劫持的客機上
I hope to be able to see your face again, baby.
我希望我能再次看見你的臉 寶貝
I love you. Bye.
我愛你 再見
We got reports of another incoming plane.
我們接到報告 還有一架飛機要撞過來
We may have to take cover in the stairwell.
我們可能要躲進樓梯間
Lieutenant Brown, Ladder 18. One of the towers just collapsed.
18雲梯隊的布朗中尉 雙塔中的一座倒塌了
- Hello, ma'am?  - Help!
- 你好 女士?  - 救命!
That tower just came down on top of everybody!
那座樓倒塌了 砸到很多人!
Are they gonna be able to get somebody up here?
能派些人上來救援嗎?
Of course, ma'am. We're coming up to you.
當然 女士 我們這就去救您
Well, there's no one here yet,
還沒有人來救援
and the floor's completely engulfed.
樓層全塌了
We're on the floor and we can't breathe.
我們被壓在樓板下面 無法呼吸了
Hold on one second, please.
堅持住
I'm gonna die, aren't I?
我會死的 是不是?
No, no, no, no, no, no!
不 不 不 不!
- I'm gonna die.  - Ma'am...
- 我會死的  - 女士...
I'm gonna die, I know it.
我知道 我會死的
Stay calm, stay calm, stay calm.
冷靜 冷靜點
Please, God.
天啊
You're doing a good job, ma'am.
您做的很好 女士
You're doing a good job. You're doing fine.
您做的很好 很好
It's so hot. I'm burning up.
好熱啊 我要燒起來了
Ma'am, you are fine. They're gonna come get you.
女士 您會沒事的 他們會救您出來的
Can anyone hear me?
還在嗎?
Oh, my God.
天啊
兩年後
沙烏地阿拉伯組織
I own you, Ammar.
我就是你的主人 阿瑪爾
You belong to me.
你是我的
Look at me.
看著我
If you don't look at me when I talk to you, I hurt you!
我說話的時候你不看著我 我就揍你!
You step off this mat, I hurt you!
你走出墊子一步 我也揍你!
If you lie to me, I'm gonna hurt you!
如果你撒謊 我一樣揍你!
Now, now look at me!
聽好了 看著我!
Look at me, Ammar!
看著我 阿瑪爾!
Come on.
來吧
Nobody talks to him.
不許跟他說話
Roger that.
收到
Are we gonna board these windows up or what?
我們不是要把窗戶釘上嗎?
Just off the plane from Washington.
剛從華盛頓飛回來吧
Rocking your best suit for your first interrogation.
穿著你最好的西服進行第一次審訊
And you get this guy.
就碰上了這傢伙
They're not always this intense.
不是每次都這麼緊張
I'm fine.
我沒事
Well, just so you know, it's gonna take a while.
你要知道 這很費時間
He has to learn how helpless he is.
要讓他知道他沒希望了
Come on, let's get a coffee.
走吧 我們去喝咖啡
No, we should go back in.
我們應該回去
There's no shame if you want to watch from the monitor.
如果你想看監視器的話 不用不好意思
All right. Huh?
好吧 來吧?
Might want to put this on.
戴上這個吧
You're not wearing one.
你不是沒戴嗎
Is he ever getting out?
他逃得出來嗎?
Never.
不可能
Let's go.
走吧
黑點 秘密基地
Right now,
現在
all this is about, simply,
其實這很簡單
is you coming to terms with your situation.
只要你意識到你的處境
It's you and me, bro.
你和我 老兄
I want you to understand that I know you,
你要知道我瞭解你
that I've been studying and following you for a very long time.
我一直在研究你 跟蹤你
I could've had you killed in Karachi,
在卡拉奇我就可以殺了你
but I didn't, I let you live,
但我沒有 我放你一條生路
so that you and I could talk.
這樣我們才能說說話
Then you beat me
然後你就
when my hands are tied.
把我雙手綁起來打
So I won't talk to you.
所以 我不會交代的
Well, life isn't always fair, my friend.
生活不是公平的 朋友
Did you really think that when we got you,
你真的以為我們抓到你後
I would be a nice fucking guy?
我還會對你那麼好?
You're a mid-level guy.
你是個中產階級
You're a garbage man in the corporation!
你是公司裡的敗類!
Why should I respect you, huh?
憑什麼我要尊重你?
Why?
為什麼?
And you're a money man.
你是個商人
Paperboy.
報童
A disgrace to humanity.
人類的恥辱
You and your uncle murdered 3,000 innocent people.
你和你的叔叔殺了三千個無辜的人
Yeah.
是吧
I have your name on a $5,000 transfer
你通過西聯匯款
via Western Union to a 9/11 hijacker.
轉了五千美金給911劫機者
And you got popped with
在你家查到有
150 kilograms of high explosives in your house!
150公斤的高爆炸藥!
And then you dare question me?
你卻來反問我?
Come on, man, I'm fucking with you.
拜託 我逗你玩呢
I don't want to talk about 9/11 yet.
我還不想談911的事
What I want to focus on is the Saudi group.
我只想談沙烏地阿拉伯組織
That there is Hazem al-Kashmiri.
這是哈齊姆·喀什米爾
And I know this dude is up to some serious shit.
而且我知道這傢伙要闖點大禍
What I want from you is his Saudi e-mail.
你把他的沙特組織郵箱告訴我
Ammar, bro, I know that you know this dude.
阿瑪爾 兄弟 我知道你認識這傢伙
Just give me his e-mail
給我他的郵箱
and I will give you a blanket.
我就給你條毯子
I will give you a blanket and some solid food.
我會給你毯子和豐盛的食物
I know that you know him.
我知道你認識他
I told you before, I won't talk to you.
我告訴過你了 我不會交代的
Have it your way. Let's go.
你自己決定的 我們動手
Come on.
來吧
When you lie to me,
你對我說謊
I hurt you.
我就揍你
- Grab me the bucket.  - Huh?
- 給我拿個桶  - 什麼?
Come on, grab the bucket!
把那個桶拿來!
Put some water in it.
裝點水進去
Come on, let's go!
快點 動手!
Come on, give it to me.
給我
Hazem was a friend of Ramzi Yousef.
哈齊姆是拉姆齊·優素福的朋友
You guys met in Iran, back in the '90s.
90年代你們倆在伊拉克見過
I don't know!
我不知道!
Fuck you!
去死吧!
Give me the e-mails of the rest of the Saudi group.
給我剩下的沙特組織成員的郵箱
Give me one e-mail and I will stop this!
給我郵箱我就停下!
Who's in the Saudi group?
沙特組織裡都有誰?
And what's the target?
目標是什麼?
Where was the last time you saw bin Laden?
你最後一次是什麼地方見到的?
Where was the last time you saw bin Laden, huh?
什麼地方見到本拉登的?
You know, when you lie to me, I hurt you.
你知道的 你撒謊 我就揍你了
This is what defeat looks like, bro.
這就叫失敗 哥們
Your jihad is over.
你們的聖戰結束了
Get him up.
把他扶起來
Try to understand the concept here.
看清狀況吧
Okay, I have time, you don't.
我有的是時間 你沒有
I have other things to do, but you don't.
我還有其他事可做 你沒有
It's cool that you're strong. I respect it, I do.
你很堅強 這很好 我尊重這點 真的
But in the end, everybody breaks, bro.
但最終 所有人都會投降
It's biology.
這是本能
巴基斯坦
Can you open the trunk, ma'am?
請打開後備箱 女士
It's clear.
安全
美國大使館 伊斯蘭馬巴德
How'd it go the other night?
那晚怎麼樣?
It was good. I mean, the local cops needed
挺好的 當地警方需要一些
a little tactical help, but he's tier fucking one, baby.
戰術幫助 但他畢竟是高層的
That's your moneymaker right there.
活脫脫一顆搖錢樹
And this is the guy that's K.S.M.'s nephew?
這就是默罕默德的侄子?
- Yeah.  - What's his issue?
- 是的  - 犯了什麼事?
He's being a dick.
他就是個混球
If he's trying to outsmart you,
如果他認為他比你聰明
why don't you tell him about your Ph.D.
為什麼你不告訴他你有博士學位
Yeah. No, but I am gonna have to turn up the heat on this asshole.
但我會讓他乖乖交代的
He needs to give up the Saudi group now.
他現在就得供出沙特組織
He's got to have that, given the family ties.
他一定知道 他們有親戚關係
He's tight with his uncle, he's got his prints all over the 9/11 money.
他跟他叔叔很親 給911事件撒了不少錢
He's got them in his head, he needs to disclose them.
他肯定知道情況 他得說出來
All right.
好的
Good.
很好
Bill, she's good to go.
比爾 她可以放行
I'll get her the right one tomorrow.
我明天會給她一個證
Was I lying or what?
我說的不對嗎?
Uh, Maya, this is Joseph Bradley,
瑪雅 這是約瑟夫·布蘭得利
our illustrious station chief.
我們傑出的站長
Joe and I did Iraq together.
約瑟和我在伊拉克共過事
It's nice to meet you.
很高興見到你
You, too, sir.
我也是 先生
How was your flight?
旅途怎麼樣?
Fine.
還好
And she's been having a great time since she got in.
她到這兒後過的都很好
Isn't that right?
對吧?
Good. How do you like Pakistan so far?
好 你認為巴基斯坦怎麼樣?
It's kind of fucked up.
挺混亂的
You volunteered for this, didn't you?
你主動請纓的 是吧?
No.
不是
Third floor, northeast corner.
第三層 東北角
You don't think she's a little young for the hard stuff?
你不覺得她還太年輕了嗎?
Washington says she's a killer.
華盛頓總部說她殺人不見血
Oh...
哦...
Children's Crusade, huh?
少年聖戰?
They want to put the next generation on the field.
他們要讓孩子上戰場
Listen, I've got a meeting with ISI in 20 minutes.
我20分鐘後和三軍情報局有個會要開
They're slow-rolling us in Lahore,
他們在拉合爾就拖延我們
you might want to bitch about that.
你應該反映一下
My fellow Americans...
美國民眾...
Did I tell you this?
我說過沒有?
That, uh, this dude in Malaysia,
馬來西亞那兒有個人
he tells the Malaysian station
他說和他侄子在馬來西亞站
that his nephew works with a guy who knows a guy...
一起工作的人知道有個人...
- Here we go.  - Hold on.
- 又來  - 別急嘛
He goes to a big feast in Bangkok about a year ago.
大概一年前 他去曼谷參加盛宴
Guest of honor?
到場嘉賓?
Usama bin Laden.
烏薩馬·本·拉登
I said, "Was Tupac there, too?"
我問 "圖派克也在那嗎?" (已故歌星)
This is worth five million bucks.
這價值五百萬美金啊
You know we're gonna have to chase it down.
我們得追蹤這線索
Hey, that's me, man, no job too small.
對我來說沒有小活
That's why I have a gift for you, my friend.
所以我有個禮物要送你 朋友
- Everyone, this is Maya.  - Hey.
- 各位 這是瑪雅  - 嘿
Maya, everyone. Please don't ask her how it's going
瑪雅 這是大家 請大家不要問她
with Ammar, 'cause she's not gonna fucking tell you.
阿瑪爾怎麼樣了 她才不會告訴你們呢
Ammar is withholding?
阿瑪爾不開口?
Washington assesses Abu Faraj is officially our new number three.
總部通知阿布·法拉赫是我們的三號目標
He's the best man for it.
他是最合適的
Uh, yeah, the London station's already asking
是 倫敦站已經在問
if he's contacting anybody in the U.K.
他在英國有沒有聯絡人
- Like we're just keeping it from them?   - Yeah.
- 以為我們瞞著他們嗎?  - 是啊
Uh, Jordanians are being really helpful with Ammar's transit papers.
約旦人給阿瑪爾的轉帳幫了不少忙
Any imminent threats in here?
有什麼大威脅嗎?
Oh, they want a consulate, a Marriott,
他們要一個領事館 萬豪酒店
it's low security.
保安差的
And they've got Majid Kahn
他們查到馬吉德·卡恩
talking about gas stations in the U.S.
談論美國的汽油站
And that's a conversation?
那是個談話?
Honestly, there are 600 questions in there.
這裡面有600個問題呢
I'd do Heathrow, the Saudis...
關於西斯羅機場 沙特...
Does it matter what Faraj thinks about Heathrow?
法拉赫怎麼想西斯羅機場的重要嗎?
How much latitude does he get to pick targets?
在目標選擇上他也沒有多少餘地吧?
I think he'll give up the Saudis,
他會供出沙特組織的
but Heathrow's gonna be tough.
但西斯羅機場得費一番事才能知道
Anyway, uh... anything from last night?
昨晚有什麼情況嗎?
Quetta base thinks they have a bead on the Arabs that escaped.
基達基地可能有逃跑的阿拉伯人的消息了
They're meeting with ISI this afternoon, hopefully set up
他們今天下午和三軍情報局會面
- a raid down there.  - Great.
- 希望能來個突襲  - 很好
And Lahore reporting
拉合爾那兒報告
ISI was painfully slow last night, again.
三軍情報局昨晚又拖延
They're beginning to think it's not incompetence.
他們開始覺得情報局並不是能力不夠
I agree. I spoke to the chief about that.
同意 我跟他們的領導談過了
- Yeah.  - Anything on bin Laden?
- 好的  - 本拉登有什麼消息嗎?
"A farmer on the Afghan border near Tora Bora reports"
"在阿富汗邊境托拉博拉附近有農民報告"
"a diamond-shaped pattern in the hills,"
"山上出現一個鑽石形狀的圖案"
"tall male in the center of the diamond"
"鑽石中有一個高大男人"
"flanked by four guards. Consistent with UBL's movements."
"四周有護衛 是本拉登一貫作風"
That's supposed to be his royal guard?
那是天兵天將嗎?
No, that's pre-9/11 behavior.
不 那是911前期行動
We have no reason to believe
我們沒理由相信
he's changed security tactics.
他更換了安全性原則
We invaded Afghanistan, that's a reason.
我們攻打阿富汗了 這就是原因
Hey, boss, I got a guy, for $5,000 bucks,
頭兒 我這有個人 他可以開著計程車
he can set up a taxi stand and snoop around a bit.
在四周打聽打聽 只要五千美金
No. Don't need him. Sorry, the diamond sighting's bullshit.
不 不需要他 對不起 鑽石圖案這事就是扯淡
Uh, see if the Paks will send someone to talk to the farmer.
看看巴基斯坦會不會派人去和那個農民談話
Anything else? No?
還有其他事嗎? 沒有了?
All right, let's put some runs on the board against Faraj, okay?
好了 我們做好準備拿下法拉赫吧 好嗎?
Talk to the case officers who didn't see fit
看看今天有哪些警官身體不適
to make it today and thank them.
好好謝謝他們
Tora Bora?
托拉博拉周圍?
- Uh-huh.  - Yeah. Good.
- 是的  - 好
Come on. Here we go. Here we go.
來吧 坐下吧
Let's just, uh...
我們...
Let's take it easy today, huh?
咱們今天來點輕鬆的 好吧?
Hungry?
餓嗎?
The food in here sucks, so I got you some of this.
這的食物不好吃 給你帶了點這個
Good, huh?
好吃吧?
Richard Reid.
理查·裡德
Oh, man, I was thinking about him.
他可真能耐
Guy gets a bomb in a shoe on a plane.
這傢伙在鞋裡藏炸彈上飛機
Un-fucking-believable.
真他媽不敢相信
You know him, don't you?
你認識他 是不是?
Yes.
是的
I'm glad you said that.
很高興你這麼誠實
I, uh, got an e-mail from you to him.
我這有一封你寫給他的郵件
I got all your coms for years, bro.
這幾年我一直在查你
Who, um...
還有誰...
Who else is in your Saudi group?
還有誰在你們沙特組織裡?
I just handed out
我只負責
some cash for them.
給他們發錢
I didn't know who the guys were.
我並不知道都有誰
When you lie to me,
當你撒謊的時候
I hurt you.
我就揍你
Please.
不要
I believe you.
我相信你
I do, I believe you.
真的 我信你
Hmm?
乖乖的 好嗎?
Good, huh?
好吃吧?
Do you want the water again?
還想再喝點水嗎?
Or do you want something else?
還是想要點別的?
Water?
水?
Please.
求你了
Just give me a name.
告訴我名字
I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know! I don't know!
我不知道! 我不知道!
Come on, let's go.
得了 我們動手
Bring him up.
把他拉起來
Here we go.
好了
You see how this works?
你知道接下來會怎麼樣吧?
You don't mind if my female colleague there checks out your junk, do you?
你不介意我的女同事看你那破玩意吧?
No?
不介意?
Good.
很好
Dude, you shit your pants?
你拉褲子了?
You stay here. I'll be back.
你待在這 我一會回來
Your friend is an animal.
他是個畜生
Please, help me.
救救我
Please.
求求你
You can help yourself by being truthful.
你說真話就能自己救自己
This is a dog collar.
這是狗鏈子
- No!  - Come on.
- 不!  - 快點
No!
不要!
Come on. Come on.
配合點
There you go. There you go.
好了 好了
You determine how I treat you.
是你讓我這麼對待你的
Huh?
是吧?
Come on. Come on.
好了
I got you.
我扶著你呢
Huh?
怎麼了?
Huh? Huh?
Come on.
走吧
走啊
You're my dog, I gotta walk you.
你是我的狗 我要溜溜你
What the fuck do you think is going on, Ammar?
你認為現在是什麼情況 阿瑪爾?
Wahleed has already told me that you know.
沃利德已經告訴我你知情
Hmm?
嗯?
Here we go. Come on, you're almost there.
好樣的 加油 你快到了
There we go. There we go.
就是這樣 就是這樣
All right. This box here, this box sucks.
好 這個箱子 很噁心
Now, I'm gonna put you in it.
現在 我要把你放進去
When is the attack?
襲擊是什麼時候?
What? What?
什麼? 什麼?
Sunday.
星期天
Sunday where? No, whoa, whoa. Sunday where?
星期天在哪個地方? 喔 喔 星期天在哪個地方?
Sunday? This Sunday or next Sunday?
星期天? 這個星期天還是下個星期天?
Where? Where?
地點? 地點?
Monday.
星期一
What?
什麼?
Tuesday.
星期二
Come on, Ammar, is it Sunday or Monday?
快點 阿瑪爾 星期天還是星期一?
Partial information will be treated as a lie.
資訊不全和說謊一樣
- Come on, let's go.  - Thursday.
- 來 我們走  - 星期四
Come on, which day is it?
快 星期幾?
Partial information, you're gonna go in the box! Huh?
信息不全 你要被塞到箱子裡了! 怎麼樣?
Partial information is treated as a lie!
信息不全等同於說謊！
Let's go!
來吧!
- Saturday!  - In the box you go.
- 星期六!  - 進箱子裡吧
Huh? In the box you go.
啊? 進箱子裡吧
Saturday!
星期六!
Come on.
來
Monday!
星期一!
Tuesday!
星期二!
- Huh? There we go.  - Friday!
- 啊? 好了  - 星期五!
Come on, let's go, come on!
來 我們走 !
Hang on, hang on, hang on, hang on, hang on.
等下 等下 等下 等下 等下
Sunday.
星期天
Monday.
星期一
Thursday.
星期四
Ammar, which day is it?
阿瑪爾 到底是哪一天?
Tuesday.
星期二
Which day?
哪一天?
Friday.
星期五
Ammar, which day?
阿瑪爾 哪一天?
Thursday.
星期四
Friday.
星期五
2004年5月29日
沙烏地阿拉伯 胡拜爾
a targeted attack against Westerners and foreigners.
一起目標為西方人和外國人的襲擊
When you look at the breakup of casualties, you can see
看傷亡人員名單就知道
that non-Muslims were killed and so were Americans.
被殺害的是非穆斯林者和美國人
Don't worry about the Saudis.
不用擔心沙特那邊
They'll take care of business.
他們能處理好的
Yeah, now.
對 現在可以
You warned them, they didn't take you seriously.
你警告了他們 他們沒拿你話當回事
This is what happens. It's not on you.
就是這樣 不怪你
Who said that, huh, Zeid? Fuck him. This is on me.
誰說的 紮伊德嗎? 去他媽 這就是我的錯
- Ammar is on me. And it's on her.  - No, no, no, no.
- 阿瑪爾的事是我的錯 也是她的錯  - 不 不 不 不
You had what? Days, brief custody, unresponsive ally?
你才有點什麼? 幾天時間 暫時扣押 不聽話的盟友?
We cannot let this be a win-win for A.Q.
我們不能讓基地組織得逞
The way you do this is look ahead.
你要做的就是眼光放長遠
London, Heathrow, mass casualties. That plan is still active.
倫敦 希思羅機場 大量人員傷亡 我們的計畫還是有用的
(2004年3月30日英國警方在希思羅國際機場附近粉碎了一起恐怖襲擊)
Ammar doesn't have a clue about what happened.
阿瑪爾不知道發生了什麼
- Oh, he knows.  - How?
- 哦 他知道  - 怎麼知道?
Oh, you have to be really careful with people
哦 你在默罕默德圈子裡混
in K.S.M.'s circle, they're devious.
得小心點 他們不是什麼善茬
He's not gonna talk about attacks on the homeland.
他不會說對我們本土的襲擊的
He's gonna withhold operational details on
他不會說出穆罕默德的行動細節
the K.S.M. network and probably bin Laden.
或者本拉登的行動細節的
But he's been in complete isolation.
但是他完全被隔絕
He doesn't know we failed. We could tell him anything.
他不知道我們失敗了 我們對他說成什麼都行
What, bluff him?
什麼 忽悠他?
He hasn't slept, Dan.
他沒睡過覺 丹
He's clueless.
他什麼都不知道
You don't remember, do you?
你不記得了嗎?
Well, short-term memory loss is
短時記憶喪失
a side effect of sleep deprivation,
是睡眠不足的副作用之一
so it should come back to you.
所以你會想起來的
I don't know.
我不知道
How can I remember?
我怎麼會記得?
After we kept you awake for 96 hours,
在我們96小時不讓你睡覺之後
you gave us the name of some of your brothers,
你給了我們一些你的兄弟的名字
and you helped save the lives of a lot of innocent people.
你幫我們救了許多無辜者的性命
Which is the smart thing to do.
明智之舉
- You're starting to think for yourself.  - Mmm-hmm.
- 你開始為你自己考慮了  - 嗯
Come on, eat up, man.
來吧 吃起來 夥計
Some hummus. Tabouleh. Don't know what that is.
豆泥 棒子麵沙拉 不知道那個是什麼
Some figs. You earned it.
還有點無花果 你應得的
So, uh, you flew via Amman to Kabul, yeah?
你從阿曼飛去喀布爾 對嗎?
Hang out with your uncle. Mukhtar.
和你的領袖叔叔在一起
How did you know that?
你怎麼知道的?
Told you, man, I know you.
早就告訴過你 夥計 我瞭解你
All right, you got me. You did, you got me.
好了 被你看穿了 被你看穿了
Flight manifests.
是航班記錄上看到的
It must be pretty fucked up for you guys after 9/11.
你們911之後過的很慘吧
What'd you do, um, what'd you do after the invasion?
之後你們在幹什麼呢?
Before you went back to Pesh.
在你回白沙瓦之前
After 9/11, we had to choose,
911之後 我們必須做出選擇
fight to protect our turf, or run.
奮起抵抗保衛祖國 或者逃跑
And you chose to fight, yeah?
而你選擇了抵抗 是嗎?
We wanted to kill Americans.
我們想殺美國人
Yeah.
對
We tried to get into Tora Bora,
我們試著進入託拉博拉
but the bombing was too high.
但是轟炸太猛烈了
We couldn't cross.
我們過不去
I'm sorry, who's the "we" in that sentence?
抱歉 句子裡的"我們"是指誰?
Me and some other guys
我和那時候在一起的
who were hanging around at that time.
其他一些人
You know, I can always go and eat with some other dude,
你懂的 我完全可以請其他人吃飯
hang you back up to the ceiling.
再把你吊在牢房
Hamza Rabia.
哈姆紮·拉比耶
Khabab al-Masri.
哈布卜·馬斯裡
And Abu Ahmed.
還有阿布·艾哈邁德
Who's Abu Ahmed?
誰是阿布·艾哈邁德?
I've heard of the other guys.
我聽說過其他人
He was a computer guy with us at the time.
他那時在我們中間是個電腦高手
After Tora Bora,
從托拉博拉離開後
I went back to Pesh, as you know.
我回到了白沙瓦 如你們所知
Mmm-hmm.
嗯
And he went north, I think.
而他去了北方 我覺得
To Kunar.
去了庫納爾
What's his family name?
他姓什麼?
Abu Ahmed al-Kuwaiti.
阿布·艾哈邁德·科威特
Abu Ahmed means "father of Ahmed." It's a kunya.
阿布·艾哈邁德意思是"艾哈邁德的父親" 父傳的
Ammar, I know the difference between
阿瑪爾 我很清楚
a war name and an Arabic name.
戰爭化名和阿拉伯名字的區別
She got you there, dude.
她識破你了夥計
I swear to you both, I don't know his family name.
我向你們發誓 我不知道他姓什麼
I would have never asked him something like that.
我根本不會問他那樣的問題
It's not how my uncle worked.
這不是我叔叔的辦事風格
I know.
我明白
My uncle told me he worked for bin Laden.
我叔叔告訴我他為本拉登工作
I did see him once.
我確實見過他一面
About a year ago, in Karachi.
大約一年前 在卡拉奇
He read us all
他給我們所有人
a letter from the Sheik.
讀了一封首領(本拉登)的信
A letter?
一封信?
What'd it say?
信裡說了什麼?
Cigarette?
抽煙嗎?
He said, "Continue the jihad."
他說:"將聖戰進行到底"
"The work will go on for a hundred years."
"這場戰爭會持續一百年"
阿布·艾哈邁德
You and I are gonna talk about some of the guys
我們得談談
in the training camps. Yeah?
在訓練營的一些人 行嗎?
Okay.
好
Some of these brothers have done some bad things.
這些人幹了一些壞事
What I want to do is I want to separate them from the people like you.
我想做的是讓你和他們劃清界限
Definitely, yeah.
一定的
All right, a guy called Abu Ahmed from Kuwait.
好 有個叫阿布·艾哈邁德的傢伙 科威特的
Yes, I remember him.
對 我記得他
A nice guy.
一個不錯的人
How close was he? What was his relationship to the leadership?
他和你們關係近嗎? 他和領導層的關係怎麼樣?
- I don't know.  - Did he eat with you guys?
- 我不知道  - 他和你們一起吃飯嗎?
Did he eat with the good guys or did he eat with the leadership?
他和好人們吃飯還是和領導層吃飯?
I don't know, sir. I have no idea about...
我不知道 長官 我不知道...
Yes, you do. You don't need an idea about...
你肯定知道 你不需要...
When you met Khalid Shaikh Mohammed,
你和哈立德·謝赫·穆罕默德見面時
was this one of the facilitators?
他幫了忙嗎?
Is this Abu Ahmed?
這個是阿布·艾哈邁德嗎?
Yes.
對
K.S.M., your boss.
穆罕默德 你的老闆
I call him Mukhtar.
我叫他領袖
Mukhtar. "Po-tay-to," you say "po-tah-to."
領袖 就像土豆和馬鈴薯 沒什麼區別
I say "fucking K.S.M.," you say "Mukhtar, " okay?
我說的"該死的穆罕默德"就是你說的"領袖"
After Mukhtar was captured,
在領袖被抓後
what did Abu Ahmed do?
阿布·艾哈邁德做了什麼?
Abu Ahmed, I believe...
阿布·艾哈邁德 我覺得...
I believe he went to
我覺得他去
to work for the Sheik.
為首領工作了
In Karachi in 2003, or 2004.
2003年或2004年在卡拉奇
He was carrying a letter from bin Laden?
他身上有本拉登的親筆信?
Is that him?
這個是他嗎?
- Is that him?  - Abu Ahmed.
- 這個是他嗎?  - 是阿布·艾哈邁德
- Say it again?  - Abu Ahmed.
- 再說一遍?  - 是阿布·艾哈邁德
Abu Ahmed. Abu Ahmed.
阿布·艾哈邁德 阿布·艾哈邁德
Abu Ahmed.
阿布·艾哈邁德
Who knows who works directly for bin Laden.
沒人知道知道為本拉登工作的有哪些人
Let's say he's part of the mix.
先假定他是為本拉登工作的一個人
Were there other people who carried messages from bin Laden?
還有其他人為本拉登傳信嗎?
Sure.
當然有
How many other people?
有多少人?
Let's talk about them.
我們說說他們
How's the needle in the haystack?
大海撈針情況如何?
Fine.
還行
Facilitators come and go.
鐵打的營盤流水的幫手
One thing you can count on in life
生活中唯一可以依靠的事
is that everyone wants money.
就是每個人都想要錢
You're assuming that al-Qaeda members
你是說基地組織成員
are motivated by financial rewards.
是被懸賞獎金誘惑
They're radicals.
他們可是極端分子
Correct.
對
You're assuming that, uh, greed won't override ideology
而你認為對一些不太堅定的成員來說
in some of the weaker members.
貪婪不會戰勝理想信念
Money for walk-ins worked great in the Cold War,
冷戰時懸賞敵人叛徒確實幫了大忙
I'll give you that.
我承認
Thank you.
謝謝
中情局黑點 波蘭 格但斯克
He says he looks like Abu Ahmed.
他說照片上的人像是阿布·艾哈邁德
Who did he work for?
他為誰工作?
It was mostly with Abu Faraj.
他大多時候和阿布·法拉赫在一起
They were always together.
他們總是在一起
What did he do for Faraj?
他為法拉赫做什麼?
He carried messages from Faraj to bin Laden
他把信息從法拉赫傳給本拉登
and from bin Laden back to Faraj.
再從本拉登把信息傳給法拉赫
We need to ask him something
我們得問他點什麼
to see if he's telling the truth.
看看他是否說了實話
We don't know if he really knew Faraj.
我們不知道他是不是真認識法拉赫
He just told me the names of all of Abu Faraj's children.
他剛剛和我說了法拉赫所有孩子的名字
I think he's telling the truth.
我覺得他說的是實話
20 detainees recognize that photo of Abu Ahmed.
20個被拘留人員認出了阿布·艾哈邁德的照片
They say he's part of an inner circle of guys
他們說他是內部人員之一
that was hanging out in Afghanistan pre-9/11.
911之前他在阿富汗
A lot of them say that after 9/11, he went to work for K.S.M.
許多人說他在911之後去為穆罕默德工作了
When K.S.M. was captured, he went to work for Abu Faraj,
穆罕默德被捕後 他去為阿布·法拉赫工作
primarily as a courier from Faraj to bin Laden.
基本算是法拉赫和本拉登之間的信使
Well, that's good, but you still...
好 很好 但是你仍然...
Yeah, but we don't know if Abu's on the outside of the network,
我們不知道阿布是否只是冰山一角
a series of cutouts and dead drops,
中間還有好多接頭員和情報點
or if he has a direct connection to bin Laden.
也不知道他和本拉登有沒有直接聯繫
I mean, does bin Laden invite him into the living room
我是說 本拉登有沒有把他邀請到客廳
and hand him a letter directly
然後直接遞給了他那封信
or is Abu just the last guy in a long line of couriers,
還是說阿布是一串信使中的最後一個
and that's why everybody knows him?
所以大家都認識他?
That's not all you don't know.
你不知道的不止這些
You don't have his real name,
你沒有他的真名
you don't have a clue of where he is.
你不知道他在哪
Yes, but we know that he's important.
對 但是我們知道他很重要
The fact that everybody's heard of Abu Ahmed,
每個人都聽說過阿布
but nobody will tell me where he is suggests that.
而沒人願意告訴我他在哪 說明他很重要
Maybe.
或許吧
Detainees could withhold his location
被拘留者可能有很多原因
for any number of reasons.
不說出他的位置
Perhaps they don't know.
或許他們不知道
Perhaps this Abu is actually a cover story
或許這個阿布其實是個幌子
and he's really a fucking unicorn.
其實他就是個獨角獸
But the withholding doesn't reveal what you want it to, does it?
但是他們不說不能證明你的想法 不是嗎?
No.
對
And if you did find him,
如果你確實找到了他
you don't know that he'd be with bin Laden.
你也不知道他是不是和本拉登在一塊
We don't know what we don't know.
不知為不知
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
他媽的那是什麼意思?
It's a tautology.
這叫同義反復
Listen, not one single detainee
聽好 沒有一個被拘留者
has said that he's been located with the big guy,
說過他和本拉登在一起
just that he delivers messages, am I wrong?
他只是傳信的 我錯了嗎?
No.
沒有
It's still good work.
不過幹得不錯
Let me know when you get some actionable intelligence.
等你得到一些可以行動的情報再告訴我
Preferably something that leads to a strike.
最好能讓我們實施打擊的
2005年7月7日
倫敦
This is what remains of the number 10 bus,
這是10號公車的殘骸
which was traveling through Tavistock Square near Euston Station.
當時它正在塔維斯托克廣場的尤斯頓地鐵站附近
There'd been explosions
爆炸還發生在了
near Liverpool Street and Edgware Road stations, too.
利物浦街附近和奇韋爾地鐵站
Dozens of the survivors were critically injured,
數十名生還者傷勢嚴重
but many of the wounded were also keen to share their stories.
還有許多傷者還足夠清醒和我們分享當時的情況
We'd just pulled out of Edgware Road.
我們剛離開奇韋爾路
And next thing I know, there's a loud, uh... A large flash of light.
接下來發生的就是... 一道閃光
Uh, felt a burning sensation on my hands,
感到手上被燒灼的劇痛
put my hands up to my face.
我用手捂著臉
I was on the floor by that point.
我那時在車廂地板上
Yeah, I can't recall anything prior to that, any noise, any bang.
之前發生的事情我都想不起來了 什麼噪音 巨響
Normal life in one of the busiest parts
首都最繁華地方的正常生活
of the capital has now been suspended,
現在已經被打亂
as just a few yards down the road here
就在離這兒幾碼的路上
they continue to care for the injured.
他們仍在醫治傷患
巴格拉姆空軍基地 阿富汗
And all around, groups of Londoners
在周圍 大批倫敦市民
are standing on corners, asking themselves
在街角站著 自言自語
中情局黑點
what has happened here and who could possibly have done this.
到底發生了什麼 這件事該怪誰
Come on.
來
You, too. Come on.
你也來
You Agency guys are twisted.
你們坐辦公室的人真變態
Detainee's ready for you.
被拘留者準備好了
Come on. Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
來 喔 喔 喔!
I want you to understand that I know you.
我想讓你明白我認識你
I've been following you and studying you for a long time.
我已經跟蹤研究你很長時間
I chased you in Lahore.
我在拉合爾追蹤過你
I had you picked up instead of killing you
我把你抓起來而不是殺了你
because you're not a violent man
是因為你不是個暴力的人
and you don't deserve to die.
你不應該死
Thank you.
謝謝
But you do have deep ties to al-Qaeda
但是你確實和基地組織有緊密聯繫
I want to ask you about
我想在你被送往
before you get sent to your next location,
下一個地點之前 問你點問題
which might be Israel.
你可能會被送到以色列
However, depending on how candid you are here today,
這取決於你今天在這裡有多坦白
I may be able to keep you in Pakistan.
我或許可以把你留在巴基斯坦
What do you want to know?
你想知道什麼?
I'm gonna ask you a series of questions
我會基於你對基地組織的瞭解
based on your knowledge of al-Qaeda
和主要資助者這一身份
and your position as key financier for the organization.
問你一系列的問題
I have dealt with the Mukhabarat.
我被帶進過穆卡巴拉(情報部門)
I have no wish to be tortured again.
我可不想再被折磨了
Ask me a question, I will answer it.
問我問題吧 我會回答的
What can you tell me about Atiyah Abd al-Rahman?
你知道阿卜杜勒·拉赫曼·阿蒂亞的事嗎?
He works for Zawahiri.
他為紮瓦赫裡工作
He's in charge of military tactics.
他負責戰術制定
In what context have you ever heard the name Abu Ahmed?
你是在什麼情況下聽說阿布·艾哈邁德這個名字的?
He works for Faraj and bin Laden.
他為法拉赫和本拉登工作
He is his most trusted courier.
他是本拉登最信任的信使
What makes you say that?
你憑什麼這麼說?
He brought me many messages from the Sheik.
他給我很多從首領那裡發來的資訊
Where did you last see him and where is he now?
你上一次見他是在哪兒 現在他又在哪兒?
You will never find him.
你們找不到他的
Why is that?
為什麼?
Even I couldn't find him.
連我也找不到他
He always contacted me out of the blue.
他總是突然和我聯繫
He is one of the disappeared ones.
他屬於那種消失的人
You know how this works?
你知道這個東西嗎?
God willing, we won't have to use it.
你乖乖的 我們就不必來硬的
Just act naturally.
表現自然點
You're in luck. I got you a one-on-one with Faraj.
你走運了 我給你安排和法拉赫一對一交談
Seriously? Thank you!
真的? 謝謝!
Don't you thank me until you hear what I want for it.
在聽到我要的東西之前先別感謝我
I want you to take care of all this before your favorite subject.
先問完這些再問你感興趣的
Deal.
成交
Don't you want to see what's in the folder?
你不想看看夾子裡寫的東西嗎?
You want family ties, financial networks,
你想要家庭關係 資金網路
media sources, disgruntled employees,
媒體管道 不得志的雇員
imminent threats, homeland plots,
鄰近的威脅 本土陰謀
foreign sales, health status, financial resources...
外貿銷售 健康狀況 財政來源...
Thank you!
謝謝!
tradecraft, recruiting tactics. Anything else?
間諜情報技術 招聘策略 還有嗎?
No, I think that covers it.
沒了 你說得挺全了
Yeah.
我也覺得
附近有拘留者 保持安靜
Huh?
什麼?
"If what they say is true,"
"如果他們說的是真的"
"the Shaolin and the Wu Tang could be dangerous."
"少林和武當可能很危險"
What do you like to be called? Faraj? Farij?
你喜歡哪個名字? 法拉赫? 法拉及?
Fuzzy? Come on.
還是法毛毛? 說嘛
Hey, what do you like? You like a bit of, uh...
嘿 你喜歡什麼? 你們喜歡 呃...
You guys like a bit of Bob Marley? Bit of reggae?
你們喜歡巴布馬利嗎? 來點瑞格舞?
Kick back, take it easy after you've blown some shit up?
搞完爆炸後放鬆一下 平靜一下?
Huh?
哈?
No?
不喜歡?
You got some Libyan music you like?
有喜歡的利比亞音樂嗎?
You did the U.K. bombings, right?
英國轟炸是你幹的 對吧?
You know, you're the second number three I've captured.
你要知道 你是我抓住的第二個三號人物了
I got K.S.M.
我還抓了穆罕穆德
Can I be honest with you?
能跟你說實話嗎?
I'm bad fuckin' news.
我就是你的末日
I'm not your friend.
我不是你的朋友
I'm not gonna help you.
所以不會手軟的
I'm gonna break you.
我會讓你崩潰
Any questions?
有問題嗎?
No?
沒有?
All right, you haven't eaten in 18 hours.
好吧 你已經18個小時沒吃東西了
We need to keep your energy up.
我們得保持你的能量
You hungry?
餓了沒?
A lot of brothers told us Abu Ahmed was Bin Laden's courier
很多兄弟告訴我們說阿布·艾哈邁德是本拉登的線人
and that he worked very closely with you.
而且他跟你走得很近
You are thinking of Abu Khalid.
你說的是阿布·哈立德
Who?
誰?
AI-Baluchi.
俾路支
My courier for the Sheik.
我和首領的信使
Okay.
好吧
So you're telling me
所以你的意思是
all the other brothers are wrong
其他所有的兄弟都是錯的
and there's some famous Baluchi guy
某位非常著名的俾路支人
working for you and Bin Laden that I've never even heard of.
為你和本拉登效力 而我從沒有聽說過
Why should you have heard of him?
為什麼你會聽說過他呢?
What does this Baluchi guy look like?
這個俾路支傢伙長什麼樣子?
Tall. Long white beard.
很高 長長的白鬍子
Thin.
很瘦
He uses a cane.
拄著一根手杖
Kind of like Gandalf.
有點像甘道夫
Who?
誰?
When was the last time you saw him?
你最後一次見他是什麼時候?
A month ago. In Karachi.
一個月前 在卡拉奇
But I don't know where he is now.
但我不知道他現在在哪
Sometimes, I wouldn't even see him.
有時 我根本就見不到他
He would just tell me
他只告訴我們
where to leave the messages.
把情報放哪
You're not being fulsome in your replies.
你的回答還不夠
You cannot force me
你不能強迫我
to tell you something I don't know.
告訴你們我不知道的東西
You do realize this is not a normal prison.
你意識到這不是普通的監獄吧
You determine how you're treated.
你決定自己被對待的方式
And your life is gonna be very uncomfortable
你的日子會非常不好過
until you give me the information I need.
除非你給我我要的情報
Where exactly is Abu Ahmed living at the moment?
阿布·艾哈邁德目前確切的住址是什麼?
Faraj is completely denying knowing Abu Ahmed.
法拉赫完全否定認識阿布·艾哈邁德
That's using every measure we have.
所有的酷刑都用過了
Well, he's either gonna keep withholding
這樣 要麼他會緘口不言
or he's gonna die from the pressure you're putting on him.
要麼他會死於你給他的壓力
Hey, you want to take a run at him?
嘿 你想不想審一輪?
No.
不想
- No?  - No.
- 不想?  - 不想
Since when no?
什麼時候開始不想的?
You know, I was meaning to tell you,
跟你說 我正打算告訴你
I'm getting out of here.
我要離開這兒
You okay?
你還好嗎?
Yeah, I'm fine, I'm just...
嗯 我沒事 只是...
You know, I think I've seen too many guys naked.
你知道 我想我已經看過太多男人裸體了
It's got to be over a fucking hundred at this point.
到現在肯定有他媽的一百多了
I need to go and do something normal for a while.
我要去做點正常的事情
Like what?
比如?
Go to Washington.
去華盛頓
Do the dance, see how that environment works.
跳跳舞 看看外界是什麼樣的
You should come with me.
你應該跟我一起去
Yeah, be my number two.
真的 跟我一起
You're looking a little strung out yourself.
你看起來虛弱得跟吸毒了似的
I'm not gonna find Abu Ahmed from D.C.
我在華盛頓可找不到阿布·艾哈邁德
They killed my monkeys.
他們殺了我的猴子
Some bullshit about escaping.
說什麼逃跑的屁話
You fucking believe that?
你相信嗎?
- Sorry, Dan.  - Yeah, I know.
- 抱歉 丹  - 是啊 我知道
Look, Maya, you got to be real careful with the detainees now.
聽著 瑪雅 你現在對拘留者要格外小心
Okay? Politics are changing,
好嗎? 政局在變化
and you don't want to be the last one
當監督委員會來的時候
holding a dog collar when the oversight committee comes.
你可不想做最後一個拿著狗鏈的人
- I know.  - Yeah?
- 我知道  - 真的?
And watch your back
回巴基斯坦後
when you get back to Pakistan.
要特別當心
Everyone knows you there now.
現在那兒的人都認識你
2008年9月20日
萬豪酒店
巴基斯坦 伊斯蘭馬巴德
Sorry.
抱歉
Fucking checkpoints.
該死的檢查點
- Maya?  - Yeah?
- 瑪雅?  - 什麼事?
We're socializing. Be social.
我們在社交場合 正常點
Okay.
好吧
Look, I know Abu Ahmed
聽著 我知道阿布·艾哈邁德
is your baby, but it is time to cut the umbilical cord.
是你的寶貝 但該是時候剪斷臍帶了
No, it's not.
不 還不到時候
So Faraj went south on you, it happens.
那就是法拉赫讓你失望了 這很正常
There are still cells in London and Spain
在倫敦和西班牙還有餘黨
who are planning the next round of attacks.
計畫下一輪的襲擊
I can work on it at the same time.
我可以同時調查
- Plus, I think it's a good thing he lied.   - No.
- 再者 我覺得他撒謊是件好事  - 不
Not at the expense of protecting the homeland, you can't...
不能以犧牲家園為代價 你不能...
Wait a minute, why is it a good thing?
等一下 為什麼是件好事?
You sound just like Bradley,
你這口氣就像布蘭得利
he doesn't believe in my lead, either.
他也不相信我的線索
It's a good thing because the fact that
說它是好事是因為
Faraj withheld on Abu Ahmed is very revealing.
法拉赫非常明顯地隱瞞了阿布·艾哈邁德的事
The only other thing Faraj lied about
法拉赫撒謊的另一件事是
was the location of Bin Laden himself.
本拉登的地址
That means Faraj thinks Abu Ahmed
這說明法拉赫覺得阿布·艾哈邁德
is just as important to protect as Bin Laden.
跟本拉登一樣需要保護
That confirms my lead.
這證實了我的線索
Or it's confirmation bias.
或者證實了偏見
Mmm.
嗯
We're just worried about you, okay?
我們只是擔心你 好嗎?
Is that okay to say?
這樣說可以嗎?
I mean, look how run-down you are.
我是說 看看你多麼筋疲力盡啊
Where's Jack?
傑克在哪兒?
Probably stuck in some checkpoint somewhere.
或許堵在哪個檢查點了吧
Mmm.
嗯
You two hooked up yet?
你們兩個勾搭上了嗎?
Hello, I work with him. I'm not that girl that fucks.
拜託 我跟他共事 我不是那種亂搞的人
It's unbecoming.
很不恰當
So? Little fooling around wouldn't hurt you.
那又怎樣? 小搞不傷身
So no boyfriend.
你沒有男朋友
Mmm-mmm.
沒有
You got any friends at all?
你到底有朋友沒?
It's Jack.
是傑克
Hey.
嘿
That's okay.
沒關係
He's stuck in traffic.
他路上堵車
Come on!
快走!
快!
出口
There's an exit!
那兒有個出口!
Oh, no! Shit.
哦 不! 靠
Come on, over here!
快來 這邊!
The blast left a crater 10 meters,
爆炸在酒店前留下了
or 30 feet wide, in front of the hotel.
徑長10米 或30英尺寬的彈坑
Police tell CNN the driver of the truck bomb
員警告訴CNN記者說汽車炸彈的司機
tried to talk his way past the hotel's steel security gate.
想說通進入酒店的鋼制安全柵欄
When armed guards said no, police said the driver
武裝守衛拒絕後 司機引爆了
detonated more than 2,000 pounds of explosives.
超過兩千磅的爆炸物
The Marriott, one of the most popular destinations for locals
萬豪酒店 對當地人和西方人來說最有名的
and Westerners in Islamabad, now destroyed.
伊斯蘭馬巴德勝地 如今被摧毀了
會議
部落領土
北巴基斯坦
The Jords have a mole!
約旦人有內鬼!
What?
什麼?
He made this video to prove his bona fides.
他做了這個視頻來證明他的誠信
Shut up!
不是吧!
Humam Khalil al-Balawi.
名叫胡馬姆·哈利勒·巴拉維
He's a Jordanian doctor.
他是個約旦醫生
He's right there in the inner circle.
他就在核心層裡
I don't buy it.
我不信
Didn't you tell me yourself nobody turns on al-Qaeda?
不是你告訴我的沒人會背叛基地組織嗎?
The Jords have worked him for a year, dinners, money.
約旦人為他效命一年了 安排宴會 籌錢
They convinced him it's his patriotic duty
他們說服他相信出賣基地組織
to turn on al-Qaeda and get rich doing it.
並由此致富是他的愛國義務
Yeah, well, so the Jords say.
這是約旦人的一面之詞
Yeah, you're right.
是的 你說的對
We can't rely on this or the Jords.
我們不能信任這個或者約旦人
We've got to evaluate him face-to-face.
我們得面對面地對質
He may not be that smart. He may be full of shit.
他或許不是那麼聰明 或許滿嘴胡言
But we have to talk to him and find out.
但我們必須跟他談話後下結論
The key is to meet him, so we can figure out
關鍵是跟他見面 這樣我們可以
for ourselves what he can actually do.
親自瞭解他的能力
He really asked for a dialysis machine?
他真的要一台血液透析儀?
Maybe we can fill the damn thing with poison.
或許我們可以給那兒玩意灌上毒藥
The meeting with Balawi's off.
巴拉維的見面取消了
He can't come to Islamabad.
他不能來伊斯蘭馬巴德
Can't or won't?
不能還是不肯?
He's not gonna travel.
他拒絕出行
Security risk.
有風險
I've said repeatedly that America doesn't torture.
我一再說美國不會使用酷刑
And I'm gonna make sure that we don't torture.
而且我會確保不用酷刑的
Those are part and parcel of an effort
這是挽回美國在世界的道德形象
to regain, uh, America's moral stature in the world.
努力中不可缺少的部分
Can you give us some sense of when you might start...
能透露一下您可能什麼時候開始...
He wants us to go to him.
他想讓我們去找他
He'll meet us in Miranshah with the Tribals.
他會和部落在米蘭沙赫跟我們見面
He knows we're white. We'd get kidnapped there.
他明知我們是白人 我們在那兒會被綁架的
Maybe do it somewhere else.
或許應該在別處見面
Germany or the U.K.? He's got a clean passport.
德國或者英國? 他有合法護照
He's not gonna travel out of al-Qaeda territory.
他不會離開基地組織領域的
And you're not going to him.
你也不能去見他
I'm not, believe me.
我不會 相信我
We're stuck.
我們困住了
What about Camp Chapman?
查普曼營地怎麼樣?
Afghanistan.
在阿富汗
That could be safe territory.
那兒可以是安全區域
查普曼營地
阿富汗 霍斯特
This may be going overboard,
或許有些魯莽行事
but I baked him a cake.
但我給他烤了個蛋糕
Muslims don't celebrate with cake.
穆斯林不用蛋糕慶祝
Don't be so literal, everyone likes cake.
別這麼誇張 人人都愛蛋糕
It's not too late for you to come, you know. It'll be fun.
你現在想來還不晚 會很有趣的
No, I don't want to be a straphanger.
不 我不想搶人風頭
It's your show, you were the first to see the potential in this.
這是你的時刻 你是第一個發現的
Oh, come on!
哦 來吧!
We've got lots of wine.
我們準備了好多酒
Cool. Bring me back a bottle.
真爽 給我帶一瓶
I will do.
我會的
Not to get technical, but this guy is actually
不談工作 但這個傢伙真的是
the first big break we've had since 9/11.
911之後第一次大突破
To big breaks and the little people
敬重大突破
that make them happen.
和幕後的小人物
So far, everything he's said
目前 他說的一切
we've cross-checked, and it's proved legit.
我們都反復核對了 證實是真的
And I think the money is persuasive.
我認為錢是很有說服力的
$25 million?
兩千五百萬?
That buys a new life.
夠開始新的人生了
Do you think he might be exaggerating his access?
你覺得他有沒有可能誇大了他的地位?
Possibly.
有可能
But al-Qaeda needs doctors, and they are short-staffed,
但是基地組織需要醫生 而他們缺少人手
and that could explain his rise.
這可以解釋他的地位上升
In six months to a year, if he doesn't fuck up,
在六個月到一年內 如果他沒有搞砸
he could be called in to treat Bin Laden.
他可能被召去治療本拉登
At that moment,
到那時候
with 25 mil on the table,
桌上放著兩千五百萬
I think he gives up the big man.
我認為他會背叛大人物的
And if he doesn't, we kill him.
如果他不配合 我們就殺了他
2009年12月30日
- John?  - Yeah.
- 約翰?  - 什麼事
When he arrives, let me set the tone,
他到了之後 讓我開場
and then I'll flip it to you
然後我會交給你
and you can talk about asset protection.
你可以跟他談資產保護的問題
Roger that.
明白
Uh, Lauren...
呃 勞倫...
I know you want to get some questions in there,
我知道你想問他問題
but give Balawi a little time after John speaks.
但是約翰說完後給巴拉維一點時間
We'll cover the basics, have his birthday cake,
我們問完基礎問題 吃生日蛋糕
then we'll get into the nitty-gritty.
然後會進入本質問題
Is that order okay? Or do you want to introduce everyone?
這個順序可以嗎? 還是你想介紹一遍大家?
I'll introduce you, you introduce your team.
我會介紹你 然後你介紹你的團隊
He knows this is a high-level meeting.
他知道這是場高層會面
Quick question.
小提問
All this taking place inside our main building?
所有這些都在我們主樓進行嗎?
Right. And, uh, Lauren,
是的 還有 呃 勞倫
Washington will want real-time updates,
華盛頓要求即時更新
so please stay on top of that.
所以請隨時準備
Be concise.
簡明扼要
The director's in the loop.
主管消息靈通
And I wouldn't be surprised
如果他不通知總統的話
if he doesn't update the President.
我不會感到意外
Yeah, I'm on it.
好 我著手去辦
Now, I just got to get his ass down here.
現在 我要去把他帶過來
Why are there gate guards there? We talked about this.
為什麼這裡有門衛? 我們討論過這點了
No one is supposed to be there when my source arrives.
當我的線人到時 不應該有人在這兒
All procedures only work
只有我們時時跟隨他
You might have spooked him already.
你們可能已經嚇到他了
- if we follow them every time.  - This is different!
- 流程才能進行  - 這次不一樣!
I'm sorry I can't explain, but it's for a good cause.
很抱歉我無法解釋 但有正當理由
Look, I'm responsible for everybody's safety, okay?
聽著 我負責每個人的安全 好嗎?
It's not just about you.
不僅僅是你的問題
I just need them to go away for a minute.
我只需要他們離開一下
You can search him as soon as he gets here.
他一到這兒你就可以搜身
All stations, this is Whiplash.
各崗位聽令 我是鞭繩
Go ahead and stand down.
先暫時退下
Copy that.
收到
Thank you.
謝謝
- 發生什麼事了? 有新消息嗎?  - 等下
- 太不可思議了  - :)
潔西嘉 19: 他來了 一會兒再聊
瑪雅 173: 真棒!
瑪雅 173: 怎麼樣 談話了嗎?
Okay, he's coming.
好了 他來了
We're gonna search him when he gets here.
他來了後我們就要搜身
Sure.
當然
瑪雅 173: 方便時回話
Okay, let's go!
好了 下車吧!
Is he supposed to limp like that?
他是這麼跛行的嗎?
Get your hand out of your pocket.
把手從口袋裡拿出來
- Hey.  - Allahu Akbar.
- 嘿  - 真主萬歲
- Hey!  - Get your hand out of your pocket!
- 嘿!  - 把手從口袋裡拿出來!
- Hey!  - Do it now!
- 嘿!  - 馬上!
- Come on.  - Do it now!
- 快  - 馬上!
Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar!
真主萬歲 真主萬歲!
173: 方便時回話
The CIA says seven of its employees
中央情報局說
were killed and six others wounded in a suicide bombing
在阿富汗某基地的自殺式爆炸中
at a base in Afghanistan.
七名雇員死亡 其他六人受傷
It was one of the deadliest attacks in CIA history.
這是中央情報局所遭受的最可怕的襲擊之一
The Associated Press has learned that the chief
美聯社瞭解到當地中情局的主管
of the CIA's post in the province is among the victims.
也在被害者之列
Former officials say she was the mother of three.
前任官員說她是三個孩子的母親
The Taliban claim responsibility for the bombing...
塔利班發表聲明對此次爆炸負責...
You okay?
你還好嗎?
Mmm.
嗯
I, um, didn't think this day could get any worse,
我 呃 本以為這一天不能再糟了
but, uh, bad news from Saudi intelligence.
但是 呃 沙特情報傳來壞消息
The courier guy,
那個信使
Abu Ahmed, is dead.
叫阿布·艾哈邁德的 死了
It's a detainee video.
這是拘留視頻
He's dead.
他死了
In Afghanistan. 2001.
在阿富汗 2001年
I buried him with my own hands.
我親手埋的他
He's dead.
他死了
In Afghanistan. 2001.
在阿富汗 2001年
No.
不
Where was this?
這是在哪兒?
Kabul.
喀布爾
No, I don't believe this. I don't believe this.
不 我不相信 我不相信
Sorry, Maya.
抱歉 瑪雅
I always liked this lead.
我一直很贊同這條線索
Fuck.
該死
Sorry, I just got here.
抱歉 我剛到
What are you gonna do?
你打算怎麼辦?
I'm gonna smoke everybody involved in this op
我要把參與這次行動的所有人化成灰
and then I'm gonna kill Bin Laden.
然後我會殺了本拉登
Right.
好吧
人為錯誤
美國大使館
I want to make something absolutely clear.
我想非常明確地說明一件事
If you thought there was some
如果你們覺得
secret cell somewhere, working al-Qaeda,
某處有些秘密人員 為基地組織效勞
then I want you to know that you're wrong.
那我要你們知道你們錯了
This is it.
這就是事實
There's no working group coming to the rescue.
沒有什麼行動小組前來營救
There's nobody else hidden away on some other floor.
沒有什麼人藏在什麼地方
There is just us.
只有我們自己
And we are failing.
我們卻失敗了
We're spending billions of dollars.
我們花著數十億的經費
People are dying!
還在死人!
We are still no closer to defeating our enemy.
還沒有向打敗我們敵人的目標前進一步
They attacked us!
他們卻襲擊了我們!
On land, in '98.
98年 從陸上
By sea, in 2000.
2000年 在海裡
And from the air, in 2001.
2001年 從空中
They murdered 3,000 of our citizens in cold blood.
他們殘忍的殺害了我們 3000位公民
And they have slaughtered our forward deployed!
還殺了我們的一線人員!
And what the fuck have we done about it, huh?
我們又他媽做了點什麼 啊?
What have we done?
我們做了什麼?
We have 20 leadership names,
我們有20個領導人的名字
we've only eliminated four of them!
我們只宰了四個!
I want targets.
我要目標
Do your fucking jobs. Bring me people to kill.
好好他媽的幹活 給我找到該殺的人
Hi. I painstakingly
嗨 我仔仔細細得
combed through everything in the system and found this.
從系統中梳理出這個
It's him.
是他
He was one of 10 names on a watch list
他是摩洛哥方面從911事件之後
sent to us by the Moroccans after 9/11.
給我們發送的10個需要監視的人之一
Ibrahim Sayeed.
伊布拉希姆·賽義德
They told us to watch out for him.
他們告訴我們要警惕他
Apparently, they think his whole family and extended family is bad
顯然 他們認為他們家和家族都有問題
and has ties to K.S.M.
而且與K.S.M有聯繫
He was picked up for fake papers and a doctored exit visa
他是在使用假證件從醫療簽證通道離開阿富汗的時候
leaving Afghanistan, traveling through Morocco
被抓的 當時正要通過摩洛哥
en route to Kuwait.
逃往科威特
Abu Ahmed al-Kuwaiti.
阿布·艾哈邁德·阿爾庫威提
This must be Abu Ahmed.
這個一定是阿布·艾哈邁德
Doesn't matter, but I wish I had that five years ago.
無所謂了 不過我希望五年前我看到了這個
How come I never saw it before?
為什麼我之前從沒見過這個?
Nobody saw it, most likely.
沒人見到 大家都一樣
There was a lot of white noise after 9/11,
911之後有很多干擾資訊
countries wanting to help out.
都是那些需要援助的國家
We got a million tips, and you know, things got lost in the shuffle.
我們收到了上百萬建議 工作 互相推諉
Human error.
人為錯誤
Anyway, I thought you should know about it.
不管怎樣 我覺得你應該知道這個
I just want to say, I've heard a lot about you.
我只想說 我聽說過你很多事
You inspired me to come to Pakistan.
是你激勵我來到了巴基斯坦
Maybe you'd let me buy you a kebab sometime.
希望有時間可以請你吃印度烤肉
Don't eat out.
別出去吃飯
It's too dangerous.
太危險了
弗吉尼亞州 蘭格利 中情局總部
Yeah?
喂?
Dan, Debbie found Abu Ahmed.
丹啊 黛比發現了阿布·艾哈邁德
Really?
真的?
Yeah. He's been in the files this whole time.
對 他一直都在我們的資料裡
The family's named Sayeed.
賽義德家族
Okay, but he's dead,
好吧 可是他死了
so doesn't that make him a little less interesting to you?
這還不能讓你對他失去興趣嗎?
He may not be.
可能沒有
We now know Abu Ahmed is one of eight brothers.
我們現在知道阿布·艾哈邁德是八個兄弟之一
All the brothers in the family look alike.
家族裡所有的兄弟相貌相似
Three of them went to Afghanistan.
三個去了阿富汗
Isn't it possible that when the three eldest brothers
難道三個最年長的兄弟在阿富汗
grew beards in Afghanistan, they started to look alike?
不可能長鬍子 長得很像了?
I think the one calling himself Abu Ahmed is still alive.
我覺得自稱阿布·艾哈邁德的那個還活著
The picture we've been using is wrong.
我們一直使用的照片是錯誤的
It's of his older brother, Habeeb.
是他哥哥 哈比蔔的
He's the one that's dead.
他才是死的那個
Okay, and what are you basing this on?
好吧 那你想證明什麼?
We have no intercepts about Abu Ahmed dying,
我們沒有收到阿布·艾哈邁德的死亡情報
we just have a detainee who said he buried a guy
我們只有一個囚犯聲稱他埋葬了一個
who looked like Abu Ahmed.
長得像阿布·艾哈邁德的人
But if someone as important as Abu Ahmed had died,
可是如果有像阿布·艾哈邁德這麼重要的人物死了的話
they'd be talking about it online
他們會大談特談的
in chat rooms all over the place.
所有的聊天室裡都會談
Plus, the detainee said that Habeeb died in 2001.
而且 那個犯人說哈比蔔是在2001年死的
We know Abu Ahmed was alive then,
我們知道阿布·艾哈邁德那時候還活著
trying to get into Tora Bora with Ammar.
企圖和阿瑪爾一起逃往Tora Bora
That means it's probably one of the other brothers
這意味著很有可能死的
In another word, you want it to be true!
換句話說 你希望這是真的!
that's dead.
是另一個兄弟
- Yes, I fucking want it to be true!  - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- 對 我他媽希望這是真的!  - 喔 喔 喔 喔
Calm down.
冷靜
I am calm.
我很冷靜
State your request.
說你的要求
Move heaven and earth,
上天入地
and bring me this fucking Sayeed family's phone number.
給我把他媽這個賽義德家的電話號碼找來
Okay, I'll go and talk to the Wolf.
好吧 我去找沃爾夫談談
As-Salaam-Alaikum.
As-Salaam-Alaikum
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam
I need a couple hundred thousand bucks.
我需要二十多萬美金
Four max.
最多四十萬
Where you gonna get that?
從哪來?
From you.
從你這
- You think so?  - Yeah.
- 你覺得呢?  - 是啊
This could crack open the facilitator
這樣可以説明我們找到一個電話
Maya's been looking for by giving us a phone number.
瑪雅正要通過這個電話打開突破口
She's your killer, Wolf. You put her in the field.
她是你的王牌 沃爾夫 是你派她去執行任務的
Come on.
行了
"Bismillah al-Rahman al-Rahim."
"Allah rewards those that strive and fight
"真主給努力戰鬥的人們的獎勵
over those that sit behind a desk."
甚於那些坐在桌子後面的"
As you know, Abu Ghraib and Gitmo fucked us.
是這樣 阿布格萊布和關塔那摩(美著名監獄)把我們搞砸了
The detainee program is now flypaper.
犯人的專案很無力
We got senators jumping out of our asses.
議員在找我們的麻煩
And the director is very concerned.
局長非常擔心
They will not stop until they have a body.
在他們看到新的目標之前不會死心的
I ran it.
是我經營的
I'll defend it.
我來保護
Done.
好的
科威特首都 科威特城
I tell you what, man,
告訴你說 夥計
it's good to be back in Kuwait.
回到科威特真好
And it's good to see you again.
再見到你也很好
Huh, it's been a while.
哈 有段時間了
I need a favor.
我需要幫助
Why I should help you?
我為什麼要幫你?
Because we're friends.
因為我們是朋友
You saying we are friend.
你說我們是朋友
How come you only call me when you need help?
為什麼只有你需要幫助的時候可以找我?
But when I need something,
而我需要幫助的時候
you are too busy to pick up the phone.
你連電話都不接
I don't think we are friend.
我覺得這不是朋友
All right, fair enough.
好吧 有道理
How about a V10 Lamborghini?
送你輛蘭博基尼V10怎麼樣?
How's that for friendship?
這算是朋友了吧?
Poor fucker had to get out of bed.
可憐的混蛋不得不起床
Hey.
嘿
- As-Salaam-Alaikum.  - Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
- As-Salaam-Alaikum  - Wa-Alaikum-Salaam
- Thank you very much for this. Appreciate it.  - You're welcome.
- 非常感謝你這麼做 感激不盡  - 歡迎
All right.
好的
- Is this a Balboni?  - Yeah.
- 這是輛Balboni嗎?  - 對
Fuck me dead.
太牛了
That's nice.
是不錯
Really nice. What are you thinking?
很不錯 你怎麼說?
Huh? Maybe a convertible? Get a bit of wind in the hair?
啊? 值嗎? 動心了嗎?
Huh? Put the top down?
哈? 可以嗎?
I think I will choose this one.
我想要這輛
Give us a minute? Thank you.
讓我們單獨談談好嗎? 謝謝
That's a nice choice, my friend.
明智之選 朋友
Speed yellow. Go big or go home, huh?
黃色跑車 太厲害了 對吧?
Nice choice.
明智之選
Sayeed?
賽義德?
Who is it?
是誰?
Who do you think?
你覺得呢?
Guy's a terrorist.
恐怖分子
His mother lives here.
他媽媽住在這
I just need her phone number.
我只要她的電話號碼
There will be no repercussions in Kuwait?
在科威特不會有影響吧?
Somebody might die, at some point, in Pakistan.
在巴基斯坦 某個地方 可能會有人死
We got a deal?
成交嗎?
諜報技術
Hey, Jack.
嘿 Jack
Sayeed family call in progress,
賽義德家的電話正在監聽
but you're not gonna like this.
不過可能結果不像你想像那樣
The Ground Branch guys are dragging their heels.
地勤人員人手不夠
There's no team deployed right now.
無人可用
Fuck.
該死
He hasn't said anything incriminating,
他什麼要緊的事都沒說
but he's at the Rawal Call Center in Rawalpindi.
不過他在拉瓦爾品第的呼叫中心
Hey!
嘿!
Why haven't you deployed a team to stay in Rawalpindi?
你為什麼不在拉瓦爾品第派一個小隊?
For one thing, it's dangerous.
其一 太危險
For another, the area is too congested for us
其二 在沒有事先得到情報的情況下
to be effective without some predictive intelligence.
那個區域對我們來說太不通暢了
Yeah, but that's why you should forward deploy,
是 可是正因如此你才應該派隊
so you can shorten your response time.
這樣才能縮短反應時間
Still, it wouldn't work.
可是 還是不行
Why?
為什麼?
The guy never stays on the phone long enough.
這個人從不會打足夠長時間的電話
You haven't tried.
你還沒試呢
Look, I don't have the personnel.
這樣 我沒有人手
That's bullshit, man.
託辭 夥計
Yeah? As it is, my guys don't get any sleep
什麼? 是這樣 我的人在巴基斯坦追蹤威脅情況
tracking the threats within Pakistan.
連覺都沒得睡
Right, I understand.
好吧 我明白了
But, you know, I don't really care
可是 其實 我才不管
if your guys get sleep or not!
你們有沒有的睡！
This guy you're obsessed with, what's his name again?
你們在研究的這個人 叫什麼來著?
Abu Ahmed al-Kuwaiti's the nom de guerre.
阿布·艾哈邁德在科威特的假名
His true name, we think, is Ibrahim Sayeed.
他的真名 我們認為 叫伊布拉希姆·賽義德
Family lives in Kuwait.
家在科威特
We've been listening in on their calls.
我們在監聽他們的電話
Wasn't it, like, eight brothers
是不是 有 八個兄弟
and a million cousins, that we know about?
還有一百萬的表親 跟以往的情況一樣?
Anyone could be calling home.
打電話的有可能是任何人
- I know.  - I mean, it's not like
- 我知道  - 我想說 不是說他
he's saying, "Hey, Mom, it's me, the terrorist."
在電話裡說 "嘿 媽 是我 恐怖分子"
Yeah, I know.
對 我知道
But, look, over the course of two months,
可是 這兩個月來
he's called from six different pay phones, from two different cities,
他用了六部不同的預付費電話 從兩個不同的城市
never using the same phone twice.
一個電話從不用兩次
And when his mother asked him where he was, he lied.
而且當他母親問他在哪的時候 他說的是假話
He said that he was in a place in the country
他說他沒出國
with bad cell reception, implying he was in the Tribals,
只是信號不好 說自己在部族地區
when in fact, he was in a market in Peshawar.
可是其實 他是在白沙瓦的一個市場裡
I'm sorry, but that's not normal guy behavior,
不好意思 這不是正常人的表現
that's tradecraft.
這是諜報手段
Well, maybe he just doesn't like his mom.
呃 可能他只是不喜歡他媽
Look, if he talks about an operation
這樣 如果他說到行動
or refers to anything remotely fishy,
或者提到任何敏感的事情
I'll get on him, okay?
我再關注他 好嗎?
No, no. Not okay.
不 不 不行
Look, Abu Ahmed is too smart
是這樣 阿布·艾哈邁德很聰明
to tip his hand by talking about ops on the phone.
絕對不會在電話裡談論行動的
He works for bin Laden.
他為本拉登工作
The guys that talk about ops
那種打電話談行動的人
on the phone don't get that job.
幹不了這個
A lot of my friends have died trying to do this.
為了這個我已經死了很多朋友了
I believe I was spared so I could finish the job.
我相信我活下來就是為了能夠完成這個任務
It is in surveillance video and pictures like this
這個是監控拍攝的畫面而畫面中
of the explosive-laden vehicle just moments before it was parked
的汽車炸彈剛剛才停下
that police hope to find the man who wanted so badly last night
警方急切得希望能夠抓到昨晚的疑犯
to leave a body count in Times Square.
正在時代廣場做傷亡統計
There are some people around the world
世界上有些人
that find our freedom so threatening
認為我們的自由是一種威脅
that they're willing to kill themselves and others
他們願意犧牲自己或者任何人的生命
to prevent us from enjoying it,
來阻止我們享受自由
but we're not gonna let that...
可是我們不會...
I really need to talk to you about beefing up
對於你加強對通話人的監視行動
our surveillance operation on the caller.
我們有必要談談了
We don't have a surveillance operation on the caller.
我們沒有對通話人執行監視行動
Someone just tried to blow up Times Square,
有人剛剛試圖炸掉時代廣場
and you're talking to me about some facilitator
而你還在跟我談什麼
who some detainee seven years ago said
有些犯人七年前說
might have been working with al-Qaeda?
曾經與基地組織很做過的人?
He's the key to bin Laden.
他是找到本拉登的關鍵
I don't fucking care about bin Laden.
我他媽不關心本拉登
I care about the next attack.
我關心的是下一次行動
You're gonna start working on the American al-Qaeda cells.
你們應該開始從美國基地組織分支上著手
Protect the homeland.
保衛本土
bin Laden is the one who keeps telling them to attack the homeland!
是本拉登讓他們一直在襲擊我們的本土!
If it wasn't for him,
要不是他
al-Qaeda would still be focused on overseas targets.
基地組織應該還把注意力放在海外的目標上
If you really want to protect the homeland,
如果你真的想保衛本土
you need to get bin Laden.
你應該抓本拉登
This guy never met bin Laden!
這個人從沒見過本拉登!
This guy's a freelancer working off the fucking Internet.
這傢伙就是個在他媽網上寫作的自由作家
No one's even talked to bin Laden in four years.
四年內都沒人跟本拉登講過話
He's out of the game.
他已經過氣了
He may well even be dead.
他可能已經死了
He might as well be fucking dead.
他他媽最好是死了
But you know what you're doing? You're chasing a ghost
可是你在幹什麼? 你在追蹤一個鬼魂
while the whole fucking network grows all around you!
還要帶著整個部門圍著你轉!
You just want me to nail some low-level Mullah-crack-a-dulla,
你想讓我盯著某些小角色
so you can check that box on your résumé that says
這樣你的履歷上就能顯示
while you were in Pakistan, you got a real terrorist!
當你在巴基斯坦的時候 有恐怖分子活動!
But the truth is, you don't understand Pakistan!
可事實是 你不懂巴基斯坦!
And you don't know al-Qaeda!
你也不懂基地組織!
Either give me the team I need to follow this lead,
要麼給我人手讓我追這條線
or the other thing you're gonna have on your résumé
要麼你的履歷上就會顯示
is being the first station chief
成為第一位因為在抓捕或者獵殺本拉登時
to be called before a Congressional committee
因為瀆職而被
for subverting the efforts
國會
to capture or kill bin Laden!
召集的領導!
You're fucking out of your mind.
你他媽的瘋了
I need four techs in a safe house in Rawalpindi,
我需要在拉瓦爾品第的駐點派四名技術人員
four techs in a safe house in Peshawar.
白沙瓦的駐點也要四個
Either send them out, or send me back to D.C.
要麼派他們過去 要麼把我派回華盛頓
and explain to the director why you did it.
並向局長解釋你為何這樣做
I've been looking for you.
我一直在找你
More importantly, he's been looking for you.
更重要的是 他一直在找你
Yesterday, your caller bought himself a cell phone.
昨天 你的通話人買了一部手機
And every time his phone rings, this phone will ring.
而每次他的手機有電話的時候 這個也會有
Did I hook you up?
我好嗎?
- Did I?  - Oh, my God!
- 好嗎?  - 哦 天呐!
I love you!
我愛你!
My guess is that he lives close
我猜測他居住的地方
to where he's making the calls.
接近他打電話的地方
And it makes sense he'd be living in Rawalpindi,
他住在拉瓦爾品第也有道理
because there's an Al Jazeera office there.
因為那裡有半島電視臺的辦事處
It'd be convenient for him to drop the tapes off
對他來說更容易發佈錄影帶
if he's messengering either from bin Laden or through an intermediary.
如果不能直接指派本拉登的送信人或者協力廠商媒體的話
So when he wants to make a call,
所以當他需要打電話的時候
he leaves the house, walks a few blocks,
他就離開家 走幾個街區
then switches on the phone.
然後打開電話
We need to keep canvassing the neighborhood until we find him.
在我們找到他之前要一直仔細排查周圍的情況
We got a shooter.
有槍手
We're blocked.
被圍了
Let me talk to them.
我來談
They said white faces don't belong here.
他們說不歡迎白人
If they don't move, shoot them.
如果他們不讓路 就打他們
He still on?
他還在打?
He's east of us. Try the market.
他在我們東側 去市場看看
Okay, heading east.
好的 去東側
Fuck.
該死
We got a signal on Tipu Road for 10 minutes.
Tipu路上有10分鐘信號
Then he went to Umar Road for five minutes.
然後他去Umar路打了五分鐘
Nogaza Road.
Nogaza路
Darya Abad, that's in the Umar Road area.
Darya Abad 在Umar路的區域
In Rawalpindi, Haider Road.
在拉瓦爾品第 Haider路
Roomi Road.
Roomi路
He went to the Convoy Road, which is near the hospital.
他去了Convoy路 醫院附近
- All right?  - Mmm-hmm.
- 好嗎?  - 嗯
So that's Haider,
那是Haider路
Roomi Road, Said, Nogaza, Taimur.
Roomi路 Said Nogaza Taimur
He made a call from Haifa Street.
他在Haifa大街打了電話
That's the spice district.
賣香料的地區
Lahore Street, which is also in Pesh, 30 minutes.
Lahore大街 也在白沙瓦 有30分鐘
Wazir Bagh Road, five.
Wazir Bagh路 五分鐘
Nishter Abad, five.
Nishter Abad 五分鐘
Phandu Road, five minutes.
Phandu路 五分鐘
The Grand Trunk Road, 45 seconds.
The Grand Trunk路 45秒
There's no pattern.
沒有規律
Sometimes he calls every two weeks, sometimes every three.
有時候他每兩周打一次 有時候三周打一次
There's no consistency.
從不連貫
I can't predict
無法預判
when he's gonna make another call
他什麼時候再打電話
'cause the guy's erratic.
因為這傢伙反復無常
Right there! Back up!
對這裡! 快!
Meanwhile, our chief foreign correspondent
同時 我們的駐外首席記者
Richard Engel confirms
理查·恩格確認
the CIA's top spy in Pakistan has been pulled out of there.
中情局的高級特工已經撤出巴基斯坦
He's been receiving death threats after being named
他已經收到了死亡威脅
publicly in a lawsuit by the family
因為一次美國導彈襲擊中
of a victim of a US drone attack.
的受害者家庭公佈了他的姓名
Richard Engel quotes a senior intelligence official
理查·恩格得知一位高級官方情報人員
as saying the officer is returning to the U.S.
聲稱長官即將調回美國
after the decision was made the terrorist threats against him, in Pakistan,
自從恐怖分子 在巴基斯坦對齊發出威脅之後
were of such a serious nature, it would not be smart not to act.
如此緊張的態勢 需要做出明智的行動
ISI fucked you.
ISI把你搞砸了
I'm so sorry, Joseph.
抱歉 約瑟夫
Still on tower three.
還在三塔
Five.
讀數五
Signal getting stronger.
信號增強了
Ten. Fifteen.
十 十五
Keep going.
繼續
Twenty. Fifteen. Ten.
二十 十五 十
Signal's getting weaker.
信號減弱了
We lost him. No signal.
跟丟了 沒信號了
Heading south.
去南邊
He's up at five again.
又到五了
Fifteen. Twenty.
十五 二十
He's moving fast.
他移動得很快
He's in a vehicle.
他在車裡
Weaker now. He's shifted.
減弱了 他換擋了
We're back to five.
回到五了
He's close by here somewhere.
他就在附近某處
I don't get it.
不明白
He's driving in circles.
他在繞圈
- No change?  - No.
- 沒變?  - 沒有
Now let's hope he comes back around.
現在希望他能再轉回來
Okay.
好的
Fifteen.
十五
Twenty.
二十
Thirty.
三十
Forty.
四十
Fifty.
五十
We're within 10 meters of him.
我們在10米之內了
Back to 40.
回到40了
He's here somewhere.
他就在這
Look at the cars. Look at the cars. He's in a vehicle.
注意車輛 注意車輛 他在車裡
The guy with the phone in the white car.
白色車裡拿電話的那個
You see him?
你看到了?
Is that him?
是他嗎?
- Could be.  - You got him?
- 有可能  - 拍到了嗎?
- Got him.  - Okay, I'm breaking off.
- 拍到了  - 好的 不跟了
The guy you've been looking for, geolocated, on his cell phone
你找的那個人 帶著電話
in his white car.
在白色車裡
Thank you.
謝謝
If you're right,
如果你說的是對的
the whole world's gonna want in on this.
全世界都會關注的
So you got to stick to your guns now.
所以你要竭盡所能了
Okay. No, it's great to speak to you, too.
好的 不 跟你談話很好
I'm amazed that you're still here.
真高興你還在
No, I can do, um...
不 我可以 呃...
Let me have a look.
讓我看看
Um, why don't we say 1:30.
呃 1:30吧
Yeah.
好
Uh, can you just hold the line, please?
呃 別掛 好嗎?
I need a picket line along the GT highway
我需要GT高速公路沿路監視
and men spaced at intervals along the road and at every exit.
還有每個出口都要有人
Maya, I know.
瑪雅 我懂
So you agree with me now, this is important.
你同意我了 這很重要
No, I've just learned from my predecessor
不 我只是從前任那裡學到了
that life is better when I don't disagree with you.
我不反對你日子才能好過些
Our current hypothesis is that he lives
我們現在的設定他居住在
somewhere along the highway, in one of the towns,
高速公路沿線 其中的一個鎮子
or a medium-sized city called Abbottabad, or up near Kashmir.
或者是一個叫做阿伯塔巴德的中型城市 或者喀什米爾附近
Kashmir's interesting because it's a way station for the Tribals.
懷疑喀什米爾是因為它是部族的落腳點
Abbottabad is interesting because we know
懷疑阿伯塔巴德是因為我們
from detainee reporting that Abu Faraj stayed there briefly in 2003.
從犯人那裡知道阿布·法拉赫在2003年曾經在那裡住過
The good news is he's driving a white SUV.
好消息是他開著一輛SUV
SUVs are actually pretty rare in Pakistan.
在巴基斯坦SUV不常見
If he was driving a sedan or a compact, we'd be fucked.
如果他開的是小車 我們可費勁了
Obviously, this assumes he doesn't change vehicles.
顯然 這表示他沒有換過車
Good morning.
早上好
Good morning, Amad.
早上好 阿瑪德
Any American in Pakistan is a target.
在巴基斯坦的美國人都是目標
They don't necessarily know I'm CIA.
他們不應該知道我是中情局的
Doesn't matter.
沒關係
You're on a list.
你在名單上
Yeah.
是
And you of all people should know that
而且你們應該明白
once you're on their list, you never get off.
一旦上了名單 就下不來了
Next time, there may not be bulletproof glass to save you.
下次 就沒有防彈玻璃保護你了
We'll keep up on the surveillance as best we can.
我們會盡力監視的
The high-res version. Can you get closer than that?
最高等級 能再近點嗎?
Yeah, we can up-res this image.
對 我們可以搞定這照片
- Make a PDF, e-mail it to me, cc George.  - Okay, that's good.
- 做成PDF 郵件給我 抄送喬治  - 好的 很好
- Thank you very much.  - Thank you.
- 非常感謝  - 謝謝
中情局總部 捕獵者海灣
I'll take that. Thank you very much.
我來處理 非常感謝
- Take that to her.  - You got it.
- 給她  - 好的
You could clean that audio as well. Just take the low end out.
你可以處理這個音訊的 隨便處理一下
Hey.
嘿
All right. So tell me how I'm doing so far.
好吧 告訴我做的怎麼樣
Basically, we got a guy who rolled with al-Qaeda
基本上 我們跟蹤到一個跟基地組織有關係的人
- and did services for him.  - Mmm-hmm.
- 而且為其服務  - 嗯
We lost him for seven years.
跟丟了七年
Now we find him again, and, boy, does he have a really nice house.
現在又發現了 而且 他住的房子不錯
Is that it?
就這個?
Pretty much.
確實是
All right, let's go talk to the boss.
好的 去找頭談談吧
Oh, you, uh... You should sit back there.
哦 你 呃... 你應該坐那邊
- Sorry.  - No.
- 抱歉  - 不
So, they're gonna ask if bin Laden is at the end of this rainbow,
所以 他們會問如果本拉登就在那裡
is the Pak military with him?
巴軍方會不會與他為伍?
The question isn't, "Are the Paks protecting bin Laden?"
而不是問 "巴軍是不是為本拉登提供保護?"
The question is, "Would he allow himself to be protected by the Paks?"
問題是 "他會允許巴軍保護他嗎?"
I mean, why would he trust them? He tried to kill Musharraf.
我想說 他為什麼會信任他們? 他曾經試圖刺殺穆沙拉夫
- Hello.  - Sir.
- 你好  - 頭
All right, go ahead.
好的 開始
So, a little context here. If you take a right out of Islamabad,
這裡的背景 就在伊斯蘭馬巴德之外
drive about 45 minutes north, you'll find yourself here in Abbottabad.
向北45分鐘車程 就能到這裡阿伯塔巴德
Now, it's a mostly middle-class community, some ex-military.
這裡 基本上是中型的社區 有些退伍軍人
Not particularly interesting to us.
對我們沒什麼價值
Except we did find this compound, which is unique.
除了這裡 很獨特
We've got a 16-foot wall around the entire perimeter.
整個建築有16尺高的圍牆
The windows are blacked out.
窗戶都封死了
There's even a seven-foot privacy wall here, so even if we got up high,
這裡還有一道七尺高的牆 所以就算我們在高處
we couldn't get a vantage point.
也沒有有利位置
I mean, it's a fortress.
我想說 這是座堡壘
Well, can't you put a camera somewhere?
呃 你們不能在這裡裝攝像頭嗎?
In these trees here, maybe?
在那些樹上 可以嗎?
Get a look into the main house?
可以觀察到房間裡的?
It'd probably be discovered.
很可能被發現
Oh.
哦
Well, we have to get a look into the house, don't we?
呃 我們必須要觀察裡面 對吧?
All right.
對
What's this, this cluster of buildings down here?
這是什麼 這一片建築?
Uh, the PMA. It's the Pakistani Military Academy.
呃 PMA 巴基斯坦軍事學院
It's their West Point.
他們的西點軍校
And how close is that to the house?
距離這裡有多近?
About a mile.
一英里左右
4,221 feet.
4221英尺
It's closer to eight-tenths of a mile.
大約十分之八英里
Who are you?
你是誰?
I'm the motherfucker that found this place, sir.
長官 我就是找到這個地點的那個混蛋
Really?
真的?
All right, I want to know more about
好的 週末之前
who's inside this house by the end of the week.
我要知道是誰住在這座房子裡
Sir.
長官
"Motherfucker."
"混蛋"
Good.
好詞
Morning, George!
早上好 喬治!
21 days.
21天了
It's been 21 days since we found the house.
我們找到這座房子21天了
Nothing's happened.
什麼都沒做
- Yeah?  - Maya, it's Steve.
- 啊?  - 瑪雅 是我斯蒂夫
Swing by. I want to show you something.
過來 給你看點東西
Okay.
好的
Okay, you can leave it paused for now, but we're gonna
好了 你可以暫停 不過我們要
- play through that, go straight...  - Hey.
- 繼續看 繼續...  - 嘿
Maya. Come see.
瑪雅 過來看
Yeah.
好
Okay, this is from a few minutes ago, okay?
好的 這是幾分鐘之前的 明白嗎?
Yeah.
明白
So remember, we've got two males,
記得 我們看到兩個男性
two females and seven kids.
兩個女性還有七個孩子
What's that?
那是什麼?
Okay, I'm saying that's Bushra, the brother's wife.
好的 我說那個是布莎拉 兄弟妻子
Well, how do you know the gender?
呃 你怎麼分辨性別的?
Well, look, this is a clothesline right here, for laundry.
嗯 看 這是晾衣繩 晾衣服的
Men don't mess with the wash.
男人不洗衣服
Okay, now, watch. It takes her about four seconds
好的 現在看 從這裡走到前門
to move from there to the front door,
她用了大概四秒
so she's on the older side.
所以她是大人
What's that up there?
那裡是什麼?
Uh, those are kids, they're shuffling around,
呃 那些是孩子 在瞎跑
sword-fighting or something with sticks.
拿著棍子在打著玩什麼的
You can see their height relative to this, these are cows.
根據這裡你可以看到身高 這些是牛
So they're probably between seven and nine.
所以他們大概七到九歲
Boys, definitely.
顯然 是男孩
Your female's moving fast.
女性移動很快
Okay, that's what I wanted to show you. Can we pause this, please?
好了 這是我要給你看的 暫停 可以嗎?
That's not the same lady.
這不是同一個女人
That's female number three.
這是第三個女人
So you found two males, three females.
所以你看到兩個男人 三個女人
That's correct.
對
So if there are three females, there ought to be three males.
所以如果有三位女性 那麼就應該有三位男性
Observing Muslim women live with their parents
顯然穆斯林女性要跟他們的父母或者
or with their husbands.
丈夫住在一起
We think there's a third family living in the house.
我們認為這座房子裡還住著一個家庭
So this third male that you've identified as possibly being bin Laden,
所以這第三個男人你認定是本拉登
do I give up all hope of ever seeing a photograph of him?
我能有希望看張照片嗎?
Hope? Yeah.
希望? 是
You give up your hope right now.
放棄希望吧
We scan for heat signatures,
我們掃描了熱成像
but we can't validate if it's a man or a woman up there.
可是我們無法證實是男人還是女人
We talked about burrowing a pinhole camera,
我們討論過用針孔攝像機
but there's a high risk of discovery.
不過有很大風險可能被發現
We found a safe house,
我們建立了駐點
but we can't get a vantage point
可是找不到有利位置
to fire a telescope over the balcony wall.
可以越過陽臺牆用望遠鏡觀察
We have explored the possibility of digging tunnels,
我們想過挖地道
of sending hot air balloons, of rerouting
或者熱氣球 還有
supply C-130s to take a peek, but that might be too alerting.
用C-130s偷拍 不過那可能會太明顯了
We've looked for ways of collecting available DNA from his trash,
我們試過通過他的垃圾收集DNA資訊
you know, looking for his toothbrush, but they burn the trash.
通過找牙刷 可是他們把垃圾都燒掉了
We started a vaccination program.
我們使用了牛痘疫苗方案
We sent a doctor to the house, see if he could pull blood.
我們派了醫生去那裡 看看能不能抽血
But that didn't work out.
可是行不通
We thought about sending a guy with a bucket
我們想過派人帶著桶
to pull a sample from the sewer to analyze his fecal matter.
去從下水道採樣分析他的糞便
What was wrong with that, exactly?
究竟是怎麼回事?
What was wrong with that? That, uh...
什麼情況? 那方法 呃...
The sample would be too diluted.
樣本被稀釋太嚴重了
And it's asking too much to get a voice confirmation
難道在他打電話的時候用音訊確認
with him on the phone?
很難嗎?
They don't make telephone calls from the compound.
他們不在裡邊打電話
We pulled the cell tower nearby.
我們已經把信號塔撤了
And I'm also gonna give up hope that
而且我也不抱希望
he might ever get in that white SUV
他會進白色SUV裡面
and drive around a bit
再開一圈
and we could see him.
讓我們看他
Don't they get groceries?
他們不買東西嗎?
The unidentified third male does not get groceries.
那個未經辨認的第三位男性不買東西
He does not leave the compound.
他從不離開那裡
He does not present himself for photographs.
也不暴露在照片裡
When he needs fresh air, he paces around beneath a grape arbor.
當他需要透氣的時候 他在葡萄樹下走走
But the leaves are so thick, they obscure our satellite views.
可是葉子太厚了 阻擋了衛星的圖像
This is a professional attempt to avoid detection.
這是專業的反偵察技巧
Okay? Real tradecraft.
好了? 這是諜報技巧
The only people we've seen behave in this way
其他我們見過如此行事的人
are other top-level al-Qaeda operatives.
都是基地組織的高層策劃人員
We did a Red Team
我們對你的分析
on your analysis.
做了檢測
According to them, this behavior could
按照這個 可能是其他的
belong to someone other than al-Qaeda.
基地組織成員
They did give a 40% chance
有百分之40的可能
that the unidentified third man
那個未經辨認的男人
is a senior al-Qaeda operative.
是一名基地組織的高層策劃人員
But they also said there's a 35% chance he's a Saudi drug dealer,
可是還有百分之35的可能他是一名沙特的毒販
15% chance he's a Kuwaiti arms smuggler,
百分之15的可能他是個科威特的軍火商
10% chance he's one of
百分之10的可能他是
the relatives of the brothers.
那個男人的兄弟
Basically, we agree with you.
基本上 我們同意你
The house screams security,
這座房子很安全
it screams someone who wants privacy,
顯示是個需要隱私的人
it even screams bad guy,
很有可能是壞人
but it does not scream bin Laden.
可是不確定是本拉登
You get the point, if you can't prove it's bin Laden,
說對了 如果你不能證明是本拉登
at least prove it's not someone else.
至少可以證明不是其他人
Like a drug dealer.
不是毒販
You know we lost the ability to prove that
當我們放棄囚犯項目的時候
when we lost the detainee program.
就已經不能證明了
Who the hell am I supposed to ask?
我他媽還能問誰呢?
Huh?
啊?
Some guy in Gitmo
在關塔那摩
who's all lawyered up?
有律師保護的人?
He'll just tell his lawyer
他會直接讓他的律師
to warn bin Laden.
警告本拉登的
You'll think of something.
你會有辦法的
He'd be the first successful drug dealer never to have dealt drugs.
他要是毒販肯定是最成功的從不接觸毒品的毒販
He has no Internet access to the house.
家裡連網路都沒有
He makes no phone calls, either in or out.
不打電話 不接也不打
Who's he selling to? Who's he buying from? How's he making his money?
他賣給誰? 從哪買? 怎麼賺錢?
And if you were to say he's retired,
如果你說他金盆洗手了
I'd say, where's the swimming pool?
我要問 他的游泳池呢?
Where's the gold cage with the falcons?
養獵鷹的金絲籠呢?
And why does he send his courier to the two cities in Pakistan
為什麼他會派他的信使去兩座巴基斯坦的城市
we most associate with al-Qaeda
兩座我們調查基地組織最頻繁的城市
that have nothing particularly to do with heroin production?
而且沒有海洛因生產的城市?
The President is a thoughtful, analytical guy.
總統很小心 很謹慎
He needs proof.
他要證明
Go ahead, you guys.
你們 先走吧
I got to say, your job...
我要說 你做的...
Hmm?
嗯?
I just don't get
我只是不懂
the rhythms of politics.
政治
Oh, you think this is political?
哦 你覺得這是政治?
If this was political, we'd be having this conversation
如果這是政治原因 我們會等十月份大選的時候
in October when there's an election bump.
再問這個問題了
This is pure risk,
這只是風險
based on deductive reasoning, inference, supposition,
關於推論的原因 論斷 猜測
and the only human reporting you have is six years old
而向你報告的那個人只比
from detainees who were questioned under duress.
那個重壓下的囚犯大六歲
The political move here is to tell you to go fuck yourself
政治家會來跟你說滾蛋
and remind you that I was in the room
在你長官剛去伊拉克服役的時候
when your old boss pitched WMD Iraq.
我都已經在這了
At least there you guys brought photographs.
至少你們還拍到了照片
You know, you're right. I agree with everything you just said.
對 你說得對 我同意你說的全部
What I meant was, a man in your position,
我想說的是 在你這個位置上的人
how do you evaluate the risk of not doing something?
不作為風險有多大?
Hmm?
嗯?
The risk of potentially letting bin Laden slip through your fingers.
讓本拉登滑過你指縫的風險
That is a fascinating question.
這是個值得思考的問題
Hey...
嘿...
I'm not saying we're gonna do it,
我們說我們要做
but the President wants to know, if we were gonna act,
可是總統想知道 如果我們做
how would we do it?
要怎麼做?
Give us options.
給我們講講
內華達州南部 51號地區
Technically, these don't exist.
從技術層面上講 這些根本不存在
I actually tried to kill this program a couple of times.
我曾經有幾次想停掉這個項目
They've gone through an initial round of testing,
只經過初始階段的測試
and they have excellent radar defeat.
非常好的反雷達效果
We just haven't tested them with people in them yet.
只是還沒有載人試驗過
You'll notice the stealth panels,
你們可以看到隱形板
similar to what we use on the B-2.
跟我們在B2隱形轟炸機機身上用的一樣
The rotors have been muffled with decibel killers.
旋翼都被消音設備處理過了
It's slower than a Black Hawk and lacks the offense and the stability,
比黑鷹要慢攻擊性和穩定性也差一些
but it can hide.
不過可以隱形
So, uh, excuse me, but what do we need this for in Libya?
所以 呃 抱歉 在利比亞我們用得著這東西嗎?
I mean, Qaddafi's anti-air is virtually nonexistent.
我想說 卡紮菲實際上根本沒有防空手段
Maya, do you want to brief him?
瑪雅 你想給他做簡報嗎?
There are two narratives about the location of Usama bin Laden.
烏薩馬·本·拉登的藏匿點有兩個說法
The one that you're most familiar with
你們聽過最多的是
is that UBL is hiding in a cave in the Tribal Areas,
他藏在部族區域的山洞裡
that he's surrounded by a large contingent of loyal fighters.
身邊有很多忠誠的戰士保護他
But that narrative is pre-9/11 understanding of UBL.
不過那是911之前的情況了
The second narrative is that he's living in a city.
另一個說法是他住在城市裡
Living in a city with multiple points of egress and entry,
居住在有很多出入口的城市裡
access to communications,
有很多聯絡點
so that he can keep in touch with the organization.
這樣他才可以跟組織保持聯繫
You can't run a global network of interconnected cells from a cave.
在山洞裡沒辦法指揮一個全球的網路組織
We've located an individual we believe,
我們鎖定了一個目標
based on detainee reporting, is bin Laden's courier.
據囚犯稱 是本拉登信使的人
He's living in a house in Abbottabad, Pakistan.
他住在巴基斯坦 阿伯塔巴德的一所房子裡
And we assess
而我們認為
that one of the other occupants of the house
房子裡的另一個居住者
is UBL.
就是拉登
General.
將軍
Excuse me.
抱歉
Uh, so, UBL, you got an intel source on the ground?
呃 那麼 拉登 有情報來源嗎?
- No.  - No?
- 沒有  - 沒有?
Okay, so how do you know it's bin Laden?
好吧 那你怎麼知道是本拉登?
'Cause the truth is we've been on this op before, it was '07,
因為事實上我們已經執行過這項任務了 在07年
and it wasn't bin Laden, and we lost a couple of guys.
就不是本拉登 我們卻損失了幾個人
Totally understand. bin Laden uses a courier
完全明白 本拉登通過一名信使
to interact with the outside world.
與外界聯繫
By locating the courier, we've located bin Laden.
通過鎖定信使 我們鎖定了本拉登
That's really the intel?
這就是情報?
That's it?
就這麼簡單?
Quite frankly, I didn't even want to use you guys,
很簡明 我也不想用你們
with your dip and your Velcro and all your gear bullshit.
用你們的人你們的裝備什麼的
I wanted to drop a bomb.
我也想扔個炸彈
But people didn't believe
可是人們認為不值得
in this lead enough to drop a bomb.
扔個炸彈
So they're using you guys as canaries,
所以他們拿你們當炮彈用
in the theory that if bin Laden isn't there,
理論上如果本拉登不在那裡
- you can sneak away, and no one will be the wiser.  - Hmm.
- 你們可以偷偷離開 沒人會知道  - 嗯
But bin Laden is there.
可是本拉登就在那
And you're gonna kill him for me.
而且你們要為我殺了他
They're nervous downtown.
氣氛有點緊張了
I don't think we'll get an approval this decision cycle.
我覺得我們肯能沒辦法獲准行動
It's her against the world.
她在對抗全世界
Oh, yeah.
哦 是
I'm about to go look the President in the eye,
我要跟總統面對面了
and what I'd like to know, no fucking bullshit,
而我想知道的是 不要廢話
is where everyone stands on this thing.
大家對此都持什麼態度
Now, very simply, is he there or is he not fucking there?
現在 長話短說 他在還是他媽不在?
We all come at this through the filter of our own past experiences.
我們都有過過去慘痛的教訓
Now, I remember Iraq WMD very clearly. I fronted that.
現在 我還記得伊拉克的事 我經歷過
And I can tell you the case for that
我可以告訴你們那比現在這個
was much stronger than this case.
嚴重多了
A fuckin' yes or a no.
他媽的是還是不是
We don't deal in certainty, we deal in probability,
我們不做擔保 我們只分析可能性
and I'd say there's a 60% probability he's there.
而我要說有百分之60的可能性他在
I concur, 60%.
我也是 百分之60
I'm at 80%. Their OPSEC is what convinces me.
我說百分之80 保密計畫說服了我
You guys ever agree on anything?
你們從來沒有統一過意見嗎?
Well, I agree with Mike.
哦 我同意麥克
We're basing this mostly on detainee reporting,
主要都是靠犯人的口供
and I spent a bunch of time in those rooms.
我也幹過
I'd say it's a soft 60, sir.
我想說不到60 長官
I'm virtually certain there's some high-value target there.
我非常確定那裡有很有價值的目標
I'm just not sure it's bin Laden.
我只是不確定是本拉登
Well, this is a little bit of a clusterfuck, isn't it?
哦 情況他媽有點複雜了 是吧?
I'd like to know what Maya thinks.
我想知道瑪雅的看法
We're all incorporating her assessment into ours.
我們都在配合她的行動
100% he's there.
百分之100他在
Okay, fine, 95%, 'cause I know certainty freaks you guys out.
好吧 百分之95 因為我知道你們不習慣擔保
But it's 100.
可是就是百分之100
They're all cowed.
他們都慫了
What do you think of the girl?
你覺得這姑娘怎麼樣?
I think she's fucking smart.
我覺得她太他媽聰明了
We're all smart, Jeremy.
我們都聰明 傑瑞米
May I join you?
我可以坐這嗎?
How is the food down here anyway?
這的伙食怎麼樣?
Uh, it's okay.
呃 還好
How long have you worked for the CIA?
你在中情局多久了?
Twelve years. I was recruited out of high school.
十二年 高中畢業就來了
And do you know why we did that?
你知道為什麼招你嗎?
I don't think I can answer that question, sir.
長官 我不知道
I don't think I'm allowed to answer.
我覺得我不可以知道
All right.
好吧
What else have you done for us?
你還為我們做過什麼?
Besides bin Laden.
除了本拉登之外
Nothing.
沒有
I've done nothing else.
別無其他
Well, you certainly have a flair for it.
哦 你肯定是有天分
炮彈
2011年 五月1日
阿富汗 賈拉拉巴德 前沿行動陣地
No. Yeah.
不 是的
All right, let's be serious, now.
好吧 咱們認真點
Don't fuck around on this one, dude.
別鬧著玩 夥計
You're just fucking around 'cause I'm up by two games.
你瞎鬧是因為我贏了兩個遊戲
How many you got?
你呢?
So, Patrick, be honest with me.
那麼 派翠克 跟我說實話
You really believe this story?
你真的相信?
I mean, no offense. No offense, I know.
我 無意冒犯 真的 我知道
But Usama bin Laden?
真是本拉登?
Yeah.
對
What part convinced you?
怎麼說服你的?
Her confidence.
她的自信
That's the kind of concrete data point I'm looking for.
這就是我要找的集中點
I tell you, buddy, her confidence
跟你說 夥計 她的自信
is the one thing that's keeping me
是使我沒有在巴基斯坦的監獄裡
from getting ass-raped in a Pakistani prison.
慫了的保證
I'm gonna be honest with you, bro.
我跟你說實話 兄弟
I'm cool with it.
我覺得不錯
Yeah?
是嗎?
Maya, I wanted you to hear it first.
瑪雅 我想讓你最先知道
You know that thing we talked about?
我們談的那件事?
It's gonna happen.
批准了
When?
什麼時候?
Tonight.
今晚
Good luck.
好運
- 50 bucks?  - 50 bucks.
- 賭50塊?  - 50塊
- 50 bucks!  - 50 bucks.
- 50塊!  - 50塊
50 bucks.
50塊
Lucky shot.
走運了
Go.
走
Apache One, you are clear.
阿帕奇一號 可以起飛了
Copy.
收到
Copy that.
Thirty seconds to first turn.
距離第一個轉向點還有三十秒
Hey, Justin, what are you listening to?
嘿 賈斯汀 你在聽什麼?
Tony Robbins.
托尼·羅賓斯
Tony Robbins, really?
托尼·羅賓斯 真的?
You should listen to it. I got plans for after this, big-time.
你該聽聽 這事完了我還有計劃 更大的計畫
I want to talk to all of you about it.
跟你們都說說
Who here has been in a helo crash before?
這裡誰經歷過直升機墜機?
Okay, so we're all good.
好吧 我們沒什麼問題了
We just crossed the border. Now entering Pakistan.
我們剛剛過了邊境 正在進入巴基斯坦
Pakistani comms, no chatter.
巴基斯坦 安靜
Three minutes. Stand by for doors open.
三分鐘 準備開門
Two minutes.
兩分鐘
Should be coming up just off our nose, 11 o'clock.
就在我們面前 11點方向
Eyes on target.
盯住目標
Stay tight.
保持警惕
Thirty seconds.
三十秒
Hey! Slide right, slide right!
嘿! 靠右 靠右!
- Too much updraft off these walls!  - Hey!
- 牆上的上升氣流太重了!  - 嘿!
We've lost power. Go to lockout.
失去動力了 準備停機
Hey!
嘿!
Hard landing.
艱難著落
Fuck!
該死!
Prince five-one is down. Prince five-one is down.
王子五一號墜落 王子五一號墜落
Black Hawk down in the animal pen.
黑鷹墜落在畜欄
This way!
這邊!
This mission is still a go. I repeat, we are a go.
繼續任務 重複 繼續任務
Alpha team is in the animal pen, making entry for AC-1.
A組在畜欄 為AC-1開路
No ropes. Wheels down.
沒有索降 直降
Prayer room's clear.
祈禱室安全
Breacher!
黏膠炸藥!
Echo team is away.
E組還沒到位
Prince five-two exiting Alpha Oscar.
王子五二號離開A區
Three, two, one. Execute!
三 二 一 炸!
Ibrahim!
伊布拉希姆!
Come on out!
出來!
- Get down!   - Down, down, down, down!
- 跪下!  - 跪下 快 快!
Down! Throw your hands in the air!
跪下! 雙手舉到空中!
Down, down, down, down! Down!
跪下 快 快! 跪下!
You've killed him.
你殺了他
All right, go, I got her.
好吧 走 我控制住了
Down, sit down.
坐 坐下
Echo 11 on perimeter.
E11號到位
Ready to breach at P-2.
準備突破P2位置
Fire in the hole.
小心炸彈
Failed breach, failed breach.
突破失敗 突破失敗
Back it up! Back it up! Main gate!
支援! 支援! 正門!
We got an unlocked door.
發現一扇沒鎖的門
Abrar.
阿布拉爾
It's okay. It's okay.
沒事的 沒事的
This is Echo 11.
我是E11
We're going to breach the main gate.
我們準備強突正門
Negative. This is Echo 01.
不行 我是E01
I'm internal, in the corridor.
我在裡邊 門廊裡
I'll let you guys in.
我放你們進來
Roger that.
明白
Shut that fucking kid up, please.
讓他媽的孩子閉嘴 拜託
Talk to me.
跟我說話
No fucking way we can blow this thing.
不可能炸開
God fucking damn it, can you pop it manually?
真他媽該死 能不能手動?
No.
不行
Alpha 3, this is Echo 11.
A3 這裡是E11
We're at our primary set point, prepping to breach.
我們在任務點 準備強突
Wait one. We're internal on the south side.
等等 我們在內部南側
This is a negative breach.
不能突破
Roger. Ready to make our entry out here.
明白 準備從這邊撤出
Yeah, roger that. We're coming to meet you.
對 明白 我們來找你們
Stay with these kids and don't let 'em in that back room.
跟這些孩子們在一起 別讓他們去後邊
- Good?  - Yeah, I'm fine.
- 還好嗎?  - 好 還好
I forgot, were we supposed to crash that helo?
我忘了 我們要炸掉那架直升機嗎?
Ibrahim tried to shoot through the door.
伊布拉希姆企圖從門內射擊
- Oh, yeah?  - I popped him from outside.
- 哦 是嗎?  - 我從門外把他幹掉了
I fucking smoked Abrar and his wife.
我他媽打死了阿布拉爾和他老婆
She still alive?
她還活著?
She's gonna bleed out.
她會死於失血過多的
- What a fucking mess.  - Yeah.
- 真是他媽一團糟  - 是
Go, go, go.
走 快
This is Echo 09.
這裡是E09
We have unknowns gathering on the southwest rooftops.
在西南側屋頂發現不明集結人群
Locked gate blocking the stairs.
門遮擋了視線
Breacher up.
準備突破
Back it up, back up.
退後 退後
Hey, back it up.
嘿 退後
Watch out.
小心
Execute.
炸
Go, go.
走 快
This is Echo 05 moving to level two.
這裡是E05正在上二層
Hakim, get those guys back.
哈基姆 讓他們回去
Khalid.
哈立德
Echo 02 moving to deck three.
E02進入三層
Clear.
安全
Hakim, get 'em back or I'll start smoking 'em.
哈基姆 讓他們回去不然我要開槍了
Wait, wait, wait.
停 等等 停
Go back, they will kill you!
回去 他們會殺了你們的!
They will kill you!
他們會殺了你們的!
Go back!
回去!
Come here!
過來!
No vest.
沒有防彈衣
All clear.
安全
Oh, fucking shit.
哦 該死
Usama.
烏薩馬
Down.
死了
All right, get him.
好的 補槍
Got a possible jackpot.
中獎了
Roger that. Possible jackpot.
收到 中獎了
Shoot.
補槍
It's okay, it's okay.
沒事了 沒事了
- Come on.  - Get down.
- 來  - 這裡
- Dude.  - It's okay.
- 夥計  - 沒事
Do you even realize what you just did?
你知道自己幹了什麼嗎?
Hey, hey, hey!
嘿 嘿 嘿!
Who is he?
他是誰?
- He is al Noori Hasan.  - Huh?
- 他是阿爾·奴裡·哈桑  - 啊?
Yo, she says it's not him.
呃 她說不是他
Talk to the kid.
問問孩子
It's okay.
沒事的
Shh.
噓
Daughter, what is his name?
小姑娘 他叫什麼?
Name, name.
名字 名字
- We need them down.  - All right.
- 帶她們走  - 好了
Okay, come on, come on. Come on.
好了 來
This is Red 02.
這裡是紅02
Geronimo.
傑羅尼莫
For God and country.
為了上帝和國家
Geronimo.
傑羅尼莫
All stations, target secure, target secure.
所有單位 任務完成 任務完成
Roger. Copy that. Target secure.
明白 收到 任務完成
Target secure. Commence SSE.
任務完成 成功
Proper SSE right now.
打掃戰場
Books, DVDs, CDs.
書籍 DVD CD
Every fuckin' hard drive. Do not leave a hard drive.
每一塊硬碟 不要留下一塊硬碟
Hey, open that for me.
嘿 幫我打開
Let's go, guys.
我們走 夥計們
Yo, what's up?
怎麼了?
I shot the third-floor guy.
我殺了三樓那個傢伙
Why don't you get to work? Grab a bag.
你怎麼不幹活? 拿個包
QRF is inbound, eight miles out.
QRF入境 距離八英里
Pak Air Force is responding.
巴空軍已反應
Fourteen minutes to intercept.
距離干預時間十四分鐘
Any station, this is Red 02. We need a body bag.
所有單位 這裡是紅02 需要屍體袋
This is Echo 09. Stand by.
這裡是E09 請等待
Hakim, I got this. Get it to them.
哈基姆 我來 給他們送去
Let's go, buddy.
我們走 夥計
Echo 05, this is Red 02. How long do you need for SSE?
E05 這裡是紅02 你們需要多長時間準備撤離?
We're gonna need at least 10 minutes, sir.
長官 至少需要10分鐘
Echo 05, you have four mikes.
E05 給你四分
This is a gold mine. I need more time than that.
這簡直是個金礦 我需要更多時間
Echo 05, if you're not at the L.Z. at four mikes,
E05 如果四分你不到集結點
I'm gonna leave your ass behind.
就他媽不接你了
The Paks have scrambled the F-16s.
巴空軍已經派出了F16
Four minutes!
四分鐘!
Prince five-two, inbound for L.Z.
王子五二 進入集結點
Where do you need the bag?
屍體袋送哪裡?
Third deck.
三層
- Here!  - Here.
- 這裡!  - 這裡
And up.
還有上邊
All right, let's move it out.
好了 出去
Let's go! Now!
走! 快!
You've got one mike to blow that downed helo.
你有一分時間炸掉那個墜落的直升機
- You all right?  - Yeah.
- 你沒事吧?  - 沒事
QRF-46 inbound for L.Z., 30 seconds out.
QRF-46進入集結點 30秒倒計時
Chopper 4-6, we are demoing 5-1.
直升機46 我們在炸51
Chopper 4-6, wave off.
直升機46 離開
4-6, wave off! Wave off!
46 離開! 離開!
Up!
抬!
Well done, Patrick.
幹得漂亮 派翠克
Thank you.
謝謝
- Move him through!  - All right, listen up, gentlemen,
- 送過去!  - 好的 聽著 先生們
read the signs.
看好標示
First floor, hard drives, files, anything!
一號 硬碟 資料 任何東西!
Second floor, opposite, down on the right!
二號 其他的 向右側放!
Third floor, ladies' underwear.
三號 女士內衣
That's right, there can't be that many of 'em, right?
好了 不會那麼多的 對吧?
- And mark all media!  - CDs, DVDs.
- 標記所有的媒體物品!  - CD DVD
- Who's got a Sharpie?  - CDs.
- 誰這麼聰明?  - CD
CDs.
CD
Right here.
這邊
Good job, man.
幹得好 夥計
- This all right?  - Move it along, bring it in.
- 就這樣? -走開 送進來
- Nice job.  - All right, all media, CDs, DVDs.
- 漂亮  - 好的 所有的物品 CD DVD
- I want 'em!  - That's all second floor right there.
- 我要!  - 都在二號位置
Who's logging on this table?
這張桌子誰管?
Where do the hard drives go?
硬碟放哪裡?
- Mark on tables.  - Yes, sir.
- 在桌子上標好  - 是的 長官
You got Ziploc bags and Sharpies, use 'em.
用文件袋和三腳架 用上
No, mark all media.
不 全都標記
Good job.
幹得漂亮
Gentlemen, watch your backs.
先生們 小心背後
Slow down!
慢點!
Thank you, sir.
謝謝 長官
- Good job.  - Slow down.
- 幹得好  - 慢點
Video cameras?
攝像機?
Video cameras, where was it found?
攝像機 哪裡找到的?
Second floor!
二層!
All right.
好的
Yes, sir. One moment, please.
好的 長官 等一下
One moment, please.
就一下 謝謝
Sir, the Agency expert gave visual confirmation.
長官 探員進行了面部確認
Yes, sir, the girl, 100%.
是的 長官 那姑娘 百分之百
Thank you, sir.
謝謝 長官
Are you Maya?
你是瑪雅?
Yeah.
對
That's the only name they gave me.
就這一個名字
You can sit wherever you want.
你想坐哪都行
You're the only one on the manifest.
你是唯一的旅客
You must be pretty important.
你肯定特別重要
You got the whole plane to yourself.
整架飛機為你一個人飛
Where do you want to go?
你想去哪?